<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>offtopic on Àlex Fiestas&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/categories/offtopic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in offtopic on Àlex Fiestas&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/offtopic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Paris until 02/11/2009</title>
      <link>/articles/in-paris-until-02112009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/in-paris-until-02112009/</guid>
      <description>As maybe you have noticed I&#39;m kinda offline these days, this is because I&#39;m in Paris in some sort of holidays. While I&#39;m here my internet/code hours will be reduced to the mornings, from 10:00 to 14:00 (local hour), I&#39;m using the rest of the day for walking trough those beautiful streets.
Well, this is it at the moment, tomorrow I&#39;ll announce something in this blog, something that lot of people has been waiting for :p</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and running again.</title>
      <link>/articles/up-and-running-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/up-and-running-again/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
After a few days of &#34;non-computer&#34; I&#39;m back with the batteries charged at 100% :) and with a small list of things to be done in the next days. This is the list:
Reach kamoso 1.0 version (I hope in 1week max):
Kamoso is the codename for a project I&#39;m doing with Aleix pol (apol) and in theory with ereslibre (he&#39;s kinda offline), is a Photobooth/Cheese clone, written in Qt/C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ok so, here we go!</title>
      <link>/articles/ok-so-here-we-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ok-so-here-we-go/</guid>
      <description>My name is Alejandro Fiestas, and I have a problem... I&#39;m a addicted to the free software. People could ask, why? what the software libre give to you? I&#39;m not sure but I&#39;ve some theories :)
The software libre gives to me the motivation I need to jump of the bed each morning thinking: come on Àlex! you&#39;ve code to write! or come on Àlex, you&#39;ve a community to help, to talk with, to work with!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
