<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Àlex Fiestas's blog - KDE stuff</title>
		<description>All my hacks related to KDE</description>
		<link>http://afiestas.org</link>
		<atom:link href="http://afiestas.org/feed.category.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Almost perfect HiDPI experience on Linux (Xorg)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/hidpi_big.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/hidpi_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Awesome HiDPI on Xorg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I bought a Macbook Pro 13” which came with a HiDPI display (also known as retina display). Already back then the support for
a single HiDPI display was quite alright with KDE4 and a few tweaks here and there. Months later Qt5 got native HiDPI support and most
applications switched from GTK2 to GTK3 and finally the outliers (chromium based apps, godot, arduino…) got support for higher DPIs as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have meant perfect support for HiDPI on linux already in 2015 or so but we are missing one important thing which is supporting
both HiDPI and normal DPI screens at the same time. In order to support HiDPI screens applications need to render themselves bigger than
they used to, how much bigger depends on the screen pixel density which, for example, in the case of my laptop is from 1.75 to 2 times
bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that applications rendered for HiDPI look huge on normal screens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hidpi-file-dialog-on-regular-screen&quot;&gt;HiDPI File dialog on regular screen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/external_noscale_big.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/external_noscale_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Open dialog looking huge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scaled-hidpi-file-dialog-on-regular-screen&quot;&gt;Scaled HiDPI File dialog on regular screen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/external_scaled_big.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/external_scaled_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Open dialog looking ok&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is where the internet seems to tell you that there is nothing to do but wait until Wayland arrives and saves us all
(I can’t wait for that btw) but that’s actually not true, X can do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRandR allows us to apply transformations on the outputs, like for example rotation, and it also allows us to scale the screens.
Scaling the screens means that X will virtually increase the amount of pixels available in the display and automatically adapt the final
image size to the actual output resolution. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a 2x2 scale transformation is applied to a 1920x1080 screen it will be seen as a 3840x2160 screen by the applications but X will magically cut that in half before sending
the image to the monitor. So we have effectively turned our normal density screen into HiDPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example of how the xrandr command line looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;xrandr --output eDP1 --auto --output DP1 --auto --scale 2x2 --right-of eDP1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will set DP1 to the default mode, scale it by 2 and place it at the right of the HiDPI laptop screen (eDP1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow&lt;/em&gt;! &lt;em&gt;Awesome&lt;/em&gt;! This is so cool! Why is everybody not doing this? Where is the catch? &lt;br /&gt;
Mostly because of one bug: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.freedesktop.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39949&quot;&gt;https://bugs.freedesktop.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39949&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read through the bug entry you will find a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.freedesktop.org/attachment.cgi?id=94929&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; created by Chris Wilson in 2014
which is shipped by default in some distributions but it has never been integrated into master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your distribution doesn’t ship with this patch by default (good for them!) you can build your own xorg-server, the patch should apply until 1.18 and for 1.19
you have a ported version &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/afiestas/xorg-server-patches/master/cursor.patch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although with this patch the experience is already way better since the applications will look correctly on all screens Qt has a few bugs
that will create weird glitches specially by placing windows where they don’t belong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;drunk-comboboxes&quot;&gt;Drunk comboboxes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-bottom:57%&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://gfycat.com/ifr/NegativeReadyBluebird&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-bottom:57%&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://gfycat.com/ifr/MilkyTanFallowdeer&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;shy-tooltips&quot;&gt;Shy tooltips&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-bottom:57%&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://gfycat.com/ifr/SlushyUnitedGrison&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;jumpy-drag-and-drop&quot;&gt;Jumpy Drag And Drop&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-bottom:57%&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://gfycat.com/ifr/DemandingFairBettong&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have been working on 3 patches that solve most of these at least in my day to day use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two still need to be reviewed and might not get accepted: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182207/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182207/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182392/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182392/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one seems to be on track to be merged (Drag and Drop): &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182391/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://codereview.qt-project.org/#/c/182391/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this patches the HiDPI experience in any modern Linux distro is as good as in macOS and the best part is that we do not have to wait until Wayland.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/almost-perfect-hidpi-on-linux/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/almost-perfect-hidpi-on-linux/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>open365, let's declare war at Google and Microsoft</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open365.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open365&lt;/a&gt; is a public and/or private cloud designed to compete with the likes
of Google Drive or Office365 by leveraging all the best free software out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service is designed to scale horizontally as well as to be resilient to components crashing or going crazy. In
order to achieve this we have implemented a microservice architecure that communicate using a bus (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rabbitmq.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rabbitmq&lt;/a&gt;) plus some
other tricks so we can scale using commodity hardware horizontally. Nothing fancy, nothing revolutionary but it had to
be done :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve integrated under the same system very well know software solutions for File sinchronization,
PIM (Email, calendar,contacts…) and office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specifically&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seafile.com/en/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Seafile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/office/kontact/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kontact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libreoffice.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Libreoffice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last two, we re using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spice-space.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SPICE&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eyeos/spice-web-client&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTML5/Javascript&lt;/a&gt; client to run those applications in the server and send only the interface to the Web browser
in a really efficient way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-how-it-looks-like&quot;&gt;This is how it looks like:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2Xqn14OtcuQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public service is in open beta so you can go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open365.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open365&lt;/a&gt; and try it out for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this blogpost we are working hard to release all the code as &lt;strong&gt;free software&lt;/strong&gt;. There is a lot to be done before we can
release all the code such as: creating a simple installer, preparing documentation and accomodating the new repositories to our CI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to release everything within days, but it will be done when it is done :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/open365-lets-declare-war-at-microsoft-and-google/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/open365-lets-declare-war-at-microsoft-and-google/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Where have I been?</title>
				<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t imagine anything worse than waking up every morning without any energy for going to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard that statement I was 17 and it made an impression on me. It made me think of how we use
our limited time, which roughly is: 1/3 sleeping, 1/3 at work and 1/3 at what we call spare time. We can’t control how much
we need to sleep, but we can take a stance on the other two thirds (work and spare time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the reason behind my disappearance, my job at BlueSystems was not fun anymore and every project I mantained at KDE
felt more like a chore than anything else. After a month of not jumping out of the bed to head to work it was time to move on.
So I passed maintainership to the people that were actually doing the job (special mention to David) and I quit my job as a full
time KDE hacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I am working at a company called eyeOS, but more on that in the next post :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate all the people that have been asking how I have been during this last year, my apologies for disappeararing without
notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/where-have-i-been/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/where-have-i-been/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>For community free of Trolls</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In light of the last comments containing insults and other attacks to members of our community I have decided to make a video blog explaining my thoughts on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video contains two separate topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanation of why we can't tolerate this behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some ideas on the actual matter (Baloo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, watch the whole thing before commenting and I hope we all work together to push away the trolls in our community.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6ewPCbbN9yY&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/for-community-free-of-trolls/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/for-community-free-of-trolls/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Desktop applications of tomorrow (I)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of three posts where I am going to share my vision for the desktop apps of the short-term future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am using my workstation or laptop I find myself spending most of my time in the browser, with it I do a lot of different tasks I used to be doing with many different native applications for example: listening to music, watching videos, chatting with friends, sending pictures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am using my tablet or phone though the situation changes. I find myself rarely using the browser, in fact I only use it to visit some site I saw on another app like Twitter or Facebook.&lt;br /&gt;
At the beginning (HTC Magic, my first Android phone) I thought this was because the browser was so unbearable that they had to come out with an alternative to the web, so they came out with &quot;specific apps&quot;, that is one app per each internet service or purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But things have evolved since, and now my Nexus5 and 7 can render websites some times even better and faster than my laptop, but anyway I still prefer to use Android apps. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both web and android apps are way better at managing content than we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They always have something to show to you: perhaps something new that might interest you? perhaps a bold guess based on you previous search? or perhaps just what is &quot;hot&quot; nearby? Two of the best example are Youtube and Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your content is available everywhere, and I am not talking only about putting stuff into the &quot;cloud&quot; but I am talking about your online profile. Continuing with the example of Youtube and Spotify on both apps you will have your: playlist, subscriptions, radios, friend list on any device either via the app or the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing content is damn easy on both either by copying the url on the Web or by clicking the omnipresent share button in Android. As a matter of fact I don't remember the last time I shared a picture or an article using a desktop app... Probably it was really long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They know what content you like... They know your habits... They know everything and they use it to provide the most convenient content at all time. Oh look! It is Monday, perhaps you want to watch the new video uploaded in this Youtube channel as you do every week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, both web and Android apps try to avoid making the user think too much which I find it to be a relief when I am using them. Again they do this by knowing what content you are interested on and by providing it to you in the best possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is it for now, In part II I will explain the current situation of the desktop apps and in part III I will show a mockup of a video app I hope to work on someday. In the meanwhile what do you think? Is the same thing I describe in this article happening to you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/desktop-applications-of-tomorrow-i/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/desktop-applications-of-tomorrow-i/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Demand a KDE Experience from your Distribution !</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this blog you probably know how things work in the GNU/Linux Desktop, some people &lt;strong&gt;develop&lt;/strong&gt; software and then some &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; people &lt;strong&gt;distribute&lt;/strong&gt; that software. This usually works quite well since the people distributing the software (In this case KDE software) work with us, and together we make sure that the final product is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system works as long as both, upstream (KDE) and downstream (Distributions) work together, but some times collaboration does not happen and problems appear. In those cases the experience that the user gets is not the experience we designed from KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite similar to what happens in the Android world, &lt;a title=&quot;HTC sense wikipedia page&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_Sense&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTC&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a title=&quot;Touchwiz interface&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touchwiz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a title=&quot;LG custom GUI&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optimus_UI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt; do their own versions of it containing a different set of applications, configurations, services, etc. Google then releases what their think &lt;a title=&quot;AOSP site&quot; href=&quot;http://source.android.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Android should be&lt;/a&gt;. In the same way Kubuntu/Opensuse/Fredora/Chakra do what they think is correct when it comes to updates, default applications, modify our software etc, meaning that in most cases the software is delivered in a different way from what we envision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I want you to demand to your distribution to offer a full KDE Experience, this means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not patching our software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrading to all minor releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using software that is no longer supported by us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offering all pre-releases as optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the latest supported middle-ware and libraries (bluez, networkmanager, udisk, Qt, virtuoso...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for distributions to do this we need to build some infrastructure we currently lack; what is the latest supported virtuoso? or the latest supported BlueZ? Currently only the respective developers know about these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we work on setting up those bits of infrastructure there are things you can already demand from your distributions - minor upgrades, no patching, or making all pre-releases available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/44428971.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-786&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/44428971.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/demand-a-kde-experience-from-your-distribution/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/demand-a-kde-experience-from-your-distribution/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>We are open for business (a KDE Hub in Barcelona)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Since January 2013 the BlueSystems office in Barcelona has been open for anybody related to KDE to join us, a great example has been Albert Vaca who has been coming to the office to work on his GSoC, some other examples are the mini Framework sprints that have been held in the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we are happy to announce that the Office is finally ready to hold sprints up to 30 people, and our intention is to hold as many sprints/KDE Events as possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office is situated in Barcelona centre:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connected to Europe via train, trip to Paris is around 6h.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well connected to the world via &lt;a title=&quot;Wikipedia El Prat page&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barcelona%E2%80%93El_Prat_Airport&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;El Prat&lt;/a&gt; airport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Around 30min from the airport in Taxi, 45min in bus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situated between &lt;a title=&quot;Paça Espanya on open streetmap&quot; href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=19/41.37496/2.14931&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Plaça Espanya &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a title=&quot;Plaça Catalunya on open streetmap&quot; href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=18/41.38662/2.16995&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Catalunya&lt;/a&gt; (two transport nexuses) [&lt;a title=&quot;Plaça Espanya, wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pla%C3%A7a_d'Espanya,_Barcelona&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;], [&lt;a title=&quot;Plaça Catalunya on wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pla%C3%A7a_de_Catalunya,_Barcelona&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it has all the commodities needed for a sprint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheap accommodation near by the office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100Mb &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiber_to_the_x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FTTH&lt;/a&gt; connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepared to setup &lt;a title=&quot;Icecream compiler site&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/icecc/icecream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;icecream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee/Projector/Whiteboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfortable &lt;a title=&quot;Ikea site&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/10196596/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keys for the sprint organizers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you are thinking on organizing a sprint know that our office is always available!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_792&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/IMG_20131214_193856.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-792&quot; title=&quot;Hackers working on KF5&quot; alt=&quot;KF5 mini sprint&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/IMG_20131214_193856.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Lat KF5 mini sprint[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_793&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/IMG_20131213_205459.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-793&quot; alt=&quot;Chess tables&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/IMG_20131213_205459.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Seconds after we finished building all 8 tables and 16 chairs[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you in Barcelona !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/we-are-open-for-business-a-kde-hub-in-barcelona/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/we-are-open-for-business-a-kde-hub-in-barcelona/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>We need a Design hero</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Solid team that I am member of, focuses on all things hardware, a few examples of our efforts are: Bluedevil, KScreen, kde-colord, powerdevil, libsolid, plasma-nm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are aware of how essential good hardware support is for having a good experience we try our best to deliver highly usable and simple interfaces that will enable any kind of user to unleash all the potential of their hardware. That is why usability is a top priority for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago something as simple as connecting into a wifi was a difficult and scary task to perform under our workspace, and most of the times it just did not work. Nowadays networking is not a problem any more, plasma-nm works reliably and we keep iterating on its design with the mission of having the most beautiful, clean and functional interface possible. And it is here &lt;strong&gt;we need your help&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need some icons to be done for Plasma-nm that integrate with the current theme. We are aware that working for somebody else's theme is not a fun job but trust me, neither is most of the hardware work we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who is going to be our design hero? Who will work with us to bring networking to the next level?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;strong&gt;help&lt;/strong&gt;, please Contact &lt;strong&gt;Jan Grulich jgrulich at redhat dot com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_780&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;178&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/plasma-networkmanagement.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-780 &quot; alt=&quot;plasma-networkmanagement&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/plasma-networkmanagement.png&quot; width=&quot;178&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Icons to be improved/re-worked.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/we-need-a-design-hero/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/we-need-a-design-hero/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 2.0 RC1, (a.k.a BlueZ5 ready)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After months of discontinued work we are happy to announce BlueDevil 2.0 !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2.0 version brings the same experience we can find in the 1.X series but using the new BlueZ5 stack which at least on our testing improves a lot the general stability and specially on sending/receiving/sharing files via Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this major version we have focused on rapidly adopting the new technology so we don't have many changes visible to the user, we have added though a few things we hope you will like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All parts of BlueDevil are now more aware of multiple adapters, wizard, bluetooth:// (kio) and system tray are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;296&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/tray.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sceenshot showing multiple adapter support in BlueDevil 2.0&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/tray.png&quot; width=&quot;296&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; BlueDevil 2.0 System Tray[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wizard is now more intelligent than before, it will connect to the right profile automatically making the setup of Mouse, Keyboard and Headsets more pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/82917338?color=ffffff&quot; height=&quot;442&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/82917338&quot;&gt;BlueDevil 2.0-RC1 wizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We need a lot of testing! This is major change for BlueDevil and even though we have done our best to make sure the first release is free of bugs it will be a miracle if that's true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill bugs at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.kde.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://bugs.kde.org&lt;/a&gt; under Solid/bluetooth version 2.0-rc1, it is important that you set the version since 2.X bugs will be given more priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I'd like to thank Daniel Schaal who did most of the work in libbluedevil and ported other bits in the applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downloads:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;As always you can find the tarballs in &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://downloads.kde.org&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/unstable/bluedevil/2.0-rc1/src/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bluedevil&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/unstable/libbluedevil/2.0-rc1/src/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;libbluedevil&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-2-0-rc1-a-k-a-bluez5-ready/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-2-0-rc1-a-k-a-bluez5-ready/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Going to Brno for a week of awesome.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sharpley.org.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Edmunson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://vhanda.in/blog/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vishesh Handa&lt;/a&gt; and I will be taking a plane from Barcelona with final destination Brno to meet for a pre-PIM sprint hackathon with the Czech KDE hackers (&lt;a href=&quot;http://ltinkl.blogspot.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lukáš Tinkl &lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://grulja.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jan Grulich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.progdan.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dan Vrátil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://martinbriza.wordpress.com/2013/10/12/you-wont-need-polkit-anymore/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Martin Bříza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://martys.typepad.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Martin Klapetek&lt;/a&gt;), is in this ocasions where one comes to appreciate that we can do our jobs from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to go this early (4 days before the actual sprint starts) because we all have to work on things with somebody close to the Brno RedHat office in a variety of topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on PowerDevil for Plasma2 (at least Lukáš and I)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving KScreen forward, fixing bugs etc (Dan and I)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE Startup (Martin K, David, Martin B and I)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE Telepathy (David and Martin K)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KPeople (Vishesh, Martin K, David)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metadata system (Vishesh and Dan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login manager (David and Martin B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't noticed, all those things have nothing to do with PIM! So it is a perfect time to introduce a new concept in KDE, the pre-sprint hackathons !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I hate being on the road, I can't wait to arrive to Brno and start this week, I'm sure it is going to be ton of fun and a lot of new things will come out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/going-to-brno-for-a-week-of-awesome/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/going-to-brno-for-a-week-of-awesome/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KScreen 1.0 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We are really glad to release the first &lt;em&gt;officially&lt;/em&gt; stable version of our new Screen Management tool that allows you to configure screens such TV, Projectors or Monitors magically just by plugging them while keeping an interface for those users that want or need a more custom configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who haven't read the previous announcements, here are the most important features of KScreen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The System Settings module:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/58253613&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/58253613&quot;&gt;KScreen System Settings module&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user13559274&quot;&gt;Àlex Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KDED (magic) Module:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/56296943&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/56296943&quot;&gt;New KDE Screen Management&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user13559274&quot;&gt;Àlex Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are already planning the &lt;strong&gt;1.1&lt;/strong&gt; but more of that in the next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download tarballs from:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/kscreen/1.0/src/kscreen-1.0.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/stable/kscreen/1.0/src/kscreen-1.0.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/libkscreen/1.0/src/libkscreen-1.0.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/stable/libkscreen/1.0/src/libkscreen-1.0.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kscreen-1-0-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kscreen-1-0-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Freedesktop Summit</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few days back I attended the first freedesktop summit/sprint where a few hackers from different free desktops met with the objective of working together. We were people from Razord-qt, GNOME, Unity and of course KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we did not had the chance to discuss all the topics I was specially interested in like Notifications or Session Inhibition I did had the chance to get involved in other topics that are equally interesting like the shared Desktop Files cache or the &quot;Trash size cache&quot; that will enable a cross desktop way of caching the size of the Trash folder getting better performance across desktops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social part of these kind of events is important as well, even though I already knew Ryan and David a week of working together makes the collaboration more smooth, and of course I also met new people as well like Lars, or Jeft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm quite happy to have pushed together with Ryan this event, we definitively moved forward the collaboration between desktops and even though freedesktop is still far from being perfect I do believe we did a step into the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't wait for the next Fd.o Summit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/freedesktop-summit/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/freedesktop-summit/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KScreen 0.1-RC1 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After a few more weeks of hard work in KScreen we are glad to announce the release of our first release candidate. We decided to jump directly from &lt;a title=&quot;KScreen alpha1&quot; href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/kscreen-0-1-alpha-released/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alpha1&lt;/a&gt; to RC because of all the great feedback we have received and the surprisingly small list of reported &lt;a title=&quot;Reported bugs&quot; href=&quot;http://goo.gl/FdLnv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll probably do another RC release to test some of the code that is not yet in this version, like supporting the restoration of manually added resolutions (something only needed for broken monitors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tarballs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/unstable/libkscreen/0.0.81/src/libkscreen-0.0.81.tar.bz2.mirrorlist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/&lt;wbr /&gt;unstable/libkscreen/0.0.81/&lt;wbr /&gt;src/libkscreen-0.0.81.tar.bz2.&lt;wbr /&gt;mirrorlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/unstable/kscreen/0.0.81/src/kscreen-0.0.81.tar.bz2.mirrorlist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/&lt;wbr /&gt;unstable/kscreen/0.0.81/src/&lt;wbr /&gt;kscreen-0.0.81.tar.bz2.&lt;wbr /&gt;mirrorlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kscreen-0-1-rc1-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kscreen-0-1-rc1-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil: Changing the way we work</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In short:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;From now on we will be maintaining only one release instead of 4. We are going to focus on 1.3 and try to fix all remaining &lt;a title=&quot;Bluedevil's bugs&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?list_id=562341&amp;amp;bug_severity=critical&amp;amp;bug_severity=grave&amp;amp;bug_severity=major&amp;amp;bug_severity=crash&amp;amp;bug_severity=normal&amp;amp;bug_severity=minor&amp;amp;bug_severity=task&amp;amp;query_format=advanced&amp;amp;bug_status=UNCONFIRMED&amp;amp;bug_status=CONFIRMED&amp;amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;amp;bug_status=NEEDSINFO&amp;amp;bug_status=VERIFIED&amp;amp;component=bluetooth&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-daemon&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kcm&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kio-bt&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kio-obex&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-systray&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-wizard&amp;amp;product=solid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bugs&lt;/a&gt;, then we will work on implementing some of the reported &lt;a title=&quot;Bluedevil's wishes&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?list_id=562342&amp;amp;bug_severity=wishlist&amp;amp;query_format=advanced&amp;amp;bug_status=UNCONFIRMED&amp;amp;bug_status=CONFIRMED&amp;amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;amp;bug_status=NEEDSINFO&amp;amp;bug_status=VERIFIED&amp;amp;component=bluetooth&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-daemon&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kcm&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kio-bt&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-kio-obex&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-systray&amp;amp;component=bluetooth-wizard&amp;amp;product=solid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wishes&lt;/a&gt; and release 1.4. Once that happens we will only maintain 1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Since BlueDevil was released we have been updating all stable versions, which means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.0 (currently at 1.0.5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.1 (currently at 1.1.5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 (currently at 1.2.4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.3 (about to release 1.3.1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been possible because the code base did not change much between releases so we fixed the bugs in the oldest version and then forwarded the fix to all the other releases, this was the easy part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before each release we like to do some intense testing to make sure that none of the basic functionality has been broken. In the hardware world quality is extremely important, we do not want to leave the user without a mouse, connectivity or an usable screen just because we are lazy or we don't feel like doing &lt;a title=&quot;Wikipedia Quality assurance&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_assurance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;QA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of BlueDevil we test most of this before each release (independently of what code has been modified): &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/Solid/Projects/BlueDevil/Tests&quot;&gt;http://community.kde.org/Solid/Projects/BlueDevil/Tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that even if the &quot;Send File&quot; functionality was NOT modified in a new release, we test it just in case something broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the list there are more or less 60 items, lets say it takes 1 minute per item to test it (it takes more) that means that it will take roughly an hour to test an entire release. Now multiply this per 4 which is the number of releases we have been doing and you will get 4 hours we invest on QA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the work we do before each release there is a constant effort of bug triaging that becomes way more difficult when you support a variety of versions since it makes you have to switch to a given version to try to reproduce and fix a bug you can't reproduce with the version you are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If it is that much trouble, why have you been doing it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;In one word: distributions. Each distribution has a different time table, each distribution has a different minor release policy, each distribution is a different world. At the time we started doing this, Bluetooth in KDE was a mess so the highest priority was to have a good experience in all distributions. It should not matter which Bluedevlil version they were using.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays the situation has changed, we work quite well in all published versions so if a distribution does not upgrade (for whatever reason) the user won't die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, now what?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;From now on we are going to maintain only one version, and we are not going to support (or give support) to any other. This means that if a bug is reported with an old version the first thing we are going to ask is to upgrade and test again (if the part that is supposedly broken has been updated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to release 1.3.1 soon, and possibly another minor release for 1.3 if we have any bugs to fix. Then we will focus on implementing some of the wishes we have been ignoring for years (sorry for that :/)  and release 1.4. Once that happens 1.3 will be automatically deprecated and only 1.4 will be supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal thoughts:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;I find it quite sad that after all this years going the extra mile so distributions can have a good Bluetooth experience, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.kde.org/?l=kde-core-devel&amp;amp;m=135689474501509&amp;amp;w=4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nobody stepped up&lt;/a&gt; to maintain stable releases. I guess this means that we are doing the right thing after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if your distribution is not shipping the latest BlueDevil version or it is not upgrading to it ask them to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If after this blog post somebody feels like taking the job of maintaining the stable releases please, kde-hardware-devel@kde.org is your list !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-changing-the-way-we-work/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-changing-the-way-we-work/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KScreen: Supporting the old and new (XRandR1.1 backend)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the points we had left to implement before we can consider KScreen a replacement for the current  screen management was support fo XRandR 1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XRandR1.1 extension dates from 100B.C and it only knows about one screen on which you can change: size,  refresh and rotation. Luckily all modern drivers implement at least XRandR 1.2 (which know about multiple screens) so you may be wondering why do we bother to support such an old thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that virtualization software usually only support XRandR1.1 and some other tools like Xvnc or Xephyr do as well, so the only way of ensuring that we look good when executed in those software is by implementing support for this old api.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine what impression will a potential user get if the first thing we do while executed in a Virtualbox is crashing? not good for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we are a step closer to consider ourselves complete :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kscreen-supporting-the-old-and-new-xrandr1-1-backend/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kscreen-supporting-the-old-and-new-xrandr1-1-backend/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.3 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Belated release announcement of the last and most stable BlueDevil release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of unique changes in 1.3 final:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;308324: Fixes crash in obexftp KDED module&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;304785: Fixes crash in obexftp KDED module (yes, another)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;311152: Fixes crash in network-dun plugin when no adapter is present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDED crashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not show PANU in kiobluetooth since it is not supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use common version number in all components (correct version reporting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always you can download it from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://download.kde.org/stable/bluedevil/1.3/src/bluedevil-1.3.tar.bz2&lt;br /&gt;
md5: 3a90e8826eb9f464084bbdafa549bf3e&lt;br /&gt;
sha256: 6dd3cca20da3ab89af1514717b969cf6d549ead4cd4f3b1f7b23ffe7e5d282e3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy it !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-3-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-3-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KScreen 0.1-alpha released !</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We are really glad to announce the first release of KScreen, the new way of managing screens in Plasma Desktop !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release comes with two main components, the System Settings module which will let you configure and arrange your screens in any way you desire, and the KDED module which will remember and restore configurations whenever it is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided to release now since we have fixed pretty much all the bugs reported by our early adopters (special thanks and hugs to them) so we feel that it is about time we let power users test it so we can fix any bug that may still exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The System Settings module:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/58253613&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/58253613&quot;&gt;KScreen System Settings module&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user13559274&quot;&gt;Àlex Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KDED (magic) Module:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/56296943&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/56296943&quot;&gt;New KDE Screen Management&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user13559274&quot;&gt;Àlex Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download tarballs from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;http://download.kde.org/unstable/kscreen/0.0.71/src/kscreen-0.0.71.tar.bz2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://download.kde.org/unstable/libkscreen/0.0.71/src/libkscreen-0.0.71.tar.bz2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked packagers to fill &lt;a title=&quot;How to install kscreen&quot; href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/Solid/Projects/ScreenManagement/Install&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this wiki page&lt;/a&gt; with instructions of how to install KScreen in their distributions, so far only Kubuntu and Arch did it :/ so ask your distribution to create packages for it !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kscreen-0-1-alpha-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kscreen-0-1-alpha-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Screen management got magic</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.progdan.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dan Vrátil&lt;/a&gt; and I are working in a brand new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.progdan.cz/2012/09/display-management-in-kde/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;screen manager &lt;/a&gt;that will solve most of the issues that we currently have on the desktop, making the configuration of monitors either auto-magical or super simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are trying be as smart as possible adapting the behavior of it to each use case making the configuration of monitors as simple as plugging them to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video is worth more than a million words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/56296943&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/56296943&quot;&gt;New KDE Screen Management&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user13559274&quot;&gt;&amp;Agrave;lex Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The behaviors are still not finished and we may change our defaults based on feedback and field test, but eh! it is a start :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to personally thanks Red Hat for sponsoring Dan and my employer BlueSystems for letting me squeeze some time to move this forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://WWW.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/redhat-logo.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; alignleft&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/blue-systems-logo300.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;113&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally if you want to get this working:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile libkscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile kscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;qdbus org.kde.kded /kded org.kde.kded.unloadModule randrmonitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;qdbus org.kde.kded /kded org.kde.kded.setModuleAutoloading randrmonitor false&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;qdbus org.kde.kded /kded org.kde.kded.loadModule kscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/screen-management-got-magic/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/screen-management-got-magic/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Giveaways in the next KDE TeaTime (#10)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Almost a month has passed since I wrote on this blog about the show, and so far everything is going great, people seem to be enjoying it and we are having a ton of fun doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I talked about it we have done 2 more shows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE TeaTime #8 - If you could change one default setting, what would it be?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wgv0etfJdNE&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wgv0etfJdNE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE TeaTime #9 - When to release?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8-pcPeUsznE&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8-pcPeUsznE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for the next one in order to properly celebrate the #10 show we have prepared some giveaways !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/capraS_xE-8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;380&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the show we will explain how to participate in the raffle so make sure to not miss it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/konqui.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Konqui giveaway&quot; src=&quot;http://afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/konqui_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;479&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheerz!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/giveaways-in-the-next-kde-teatime-10/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/giveaways-in-the-next-kde-teatime-10/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KDEPIM sprint #2 (Understanding and diagnosing Akonadi)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In this second part I'm going to explain a few techniques to debug Akonadi we use in order to understand why my KMail installation was working bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My configuration&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;I'm a heavy email user, every day  I receive and read hundreds of them, and I love to have my email synchronized across devices (laptop, workstation, phone, tablet) and particulary in my laptop and workstation I want to have all my email &lt;em&gt;offline&lt;/em&gt; so I can make use of it with or without internet, specially useful on my laptop while traveling. Because of all those reasons I have to use something called Disconnect IMAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My EMail account&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The account has 5.6GB of data and according to GMail it is split in 700K emails (more or less) 200K of those emails are in a folder (label in GMail) called kde-commits with a size of 1.8GB, then it has 5 folders with more than 25K emails and around 200MB of data each, and finally the rest are just small folders with 500-5000 emails. In total there are 70 folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First import experience&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The first problem I have with KMail2 is the experience out of the first email import. Since my account is so huge it takes a while (around 15 hours) to make the full import and I can't use the application while doing it because either the data won't be available or all my CPU power will be used in the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix this we designed something called &quot;Spanish sync&quot; which basically consist on splitting the task of &quot;Downloading all email while indexing it&quot; into the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download all the envelopes (subject,from, to, and some other data) starting from the most recent. Once this is done KMail will be fully functional (full email will be downloaded when user tries to read it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download in a controlled way all the email bodies (where the content of the email is). Right now this goes as fast as your internet line allows which can be a problem for people having a fast internet connection (100Mb in my case) and slow machine (my laptop is 6yrs old). Once this finishes the email content will be available offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally we will index all emails. If the user tries to search before this is done we will show an progress indicator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full synchronization of my email is still going to take 15 hours but I will be able to use my application almost since moment one (since it will import most recent emails first).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KMail not showing email body&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Even though I set my account as &quot;Disconnected IMAP&quot;, more or less 50% of my emails were not being downloaded so I kept getting this &quot;loading email&quot; message from KMail. This is specially annoying when I'm on my laptop since the internet availability while traveling is not reliable. We have not been able to identify the reason why 1 out 2 emails is not being downloaded but at least I learned how to diagnose this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Execute the debugging application &quot;akonadiconsole&quot; and go to the &quot;DB console&quot; tab and execute the following SQL query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;SELECT count(*) FROM parttable WHERE name = &quot;PLD:RFC822&quot; AND data is null;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;Change notification log&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/change-notification.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result should be a small amount of your total email (in my workstation it is 4K while in my laptop it is 300K). If you set your account as &quot;Disconnected IMAP&quot; and you are getting a high number you may be suffering the same bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no way to force Akonadi to download the missing body for all those emails... so you will have to either live with it or re-import your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KMail not updating email status, not loading anything, not working&lt;/strong&gt; !&lt;br /&gt;
If all your email is offline and you do not suffer from the bug I mentioned before, you won't even notice this... but if you are using &quot;Normal IMAP&quot; or you suffer the bug this is the most annoying behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically all the actions you perform are put in a queue to be processed, for example if you read 100 emails while offline, those &quot;100 read actions&quot; will be stored locally and pushed to the server once online. Where is the problem? the problem is that right now &quot;pushing&quot; this information blocks any other operation to be sure that we are using fresh data so if for instance email XXX is requested akonadi won't provide it until the the &quot;pushing&quot; finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most IMAP servers pushing this data is FAST, but for some reason in GMail each modification takes around 1/2 seconds... so if I set as read 100 email or I delete 2000 make the math :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution for this is conceptually quite easy, we should only block operations that affect email XXX instead of blocking everything. The technical implementation is a little more difficult than that :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use akonadiconsole to check this &quot;todo list&quot;, open it go to &quot;Agents&quot; tab, and in there open the context menu on the agent you want to check and click on &quot;show change-notification log&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/emails-without-payload.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Email without payload sql query&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/emails-without-payload-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Akonadi and Kontact2 are an awesome piece of software, I have no doubts that once the issues I mentioned here are fixed we will offer a better user experience than the one you get either in osx or Thunderbird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note, Thunderbird or iMail take also 15 hour to fetch all my email, with the difference that I can use my email right the way, we are not that far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a screenshot of how I'd like KMail to look like by default... and I'm not the only one asking this :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/kmail.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;KMail awesome config&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/kmail-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: to have this config just do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Settings--&amp;gt;Appearance--&amp;gt;Layout--&amp;gt;Show the message preview pane next to the message list&lt;br /&gt;
Settings-&amp;gt;Appearance--&amp;gt;Message List--&amp;gt;Default Thene: Fancy with Clickable Status&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kdepim-sprint-2-understanding-and-diagnosing-akonadi/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kdepim-sprint-2-understanding-and-diagnosing-akonadi/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Results from my first KDEPIM sprint #1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I went to Berlin, this time to attend the October KDEPIM sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I have met some PIM hackers through the years I have been around KDE, I never had the opportunity to actually work with them, and try to figure things out, and as it is usual in our community they haven't disappointed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had 2 objectives for this sprint, first get a few bugs that I discover while working on WebAccounts fixed, and secondly try to track down all the KMail issues I have when I run it in my laptop. In this blog post I will only cover the first block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collections that can't be de/activated&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really stupid bug, but in my humble opinion these are the kind of things that makes the user feel that they are using inferior quality software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take a look at the following pic, you will see how there is a checkbox left of my email address that apparently will activate or deactivate all the contact groups provided by my Google account, well it doesn't do anything so clicking on it results on basically nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;Resources bug&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/resources.png&quot; alt=&quot;Resources bug&quot; width=&quot;256&quot; height=&quot;94&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to fix it and successfully tracked the bug down to a piece of code, but I needed help from the PIM hackers to actually fix it, and of course they didn't disappointed, in a matter of hours it was fixed :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KMail and the &quot;Broken&quot; imap resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after a new IMAP resource was added (doesn't matter if from KMail or Kontact or any other method) a notification will appear saying that the IMAP resource is broken. Wait what? is it broken? if I have just added it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;KMAil broken notification&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/notification.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;465&quot; height=&quot;104&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, not this is fixed since KMail now knows how to differentiate between a broken IMAP resource and one that has not been yet configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activate resources when added&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another small bug or behavior that really bothers me is that when a new resource is added (for example a Google account is configured), the new added Calendars or Agendas won't be &quot;activated/checked&quot; by default. I think that if you just added something is because you want to use it, don't you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this problem may seem simple but it isn't, so after taking a look at it with the PIM hackers we thought a good way to fix it, though we didn't had time to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.kde.org/?l=kde-pim&amp;amp;m=135040360317368&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;http://lists.kde.org/?l=kde-pim&amp;amp;m=135040360317368&amp;amp;w=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nobody does, I will try to fix it when possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in part 2!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/results-from-my-first-kdepim-sprint-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/results-from-my-first-kdepim-sprint-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meet the KDE TeaTime !</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;KDE TeaTime Logo&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/ktt.png&quot; alt=&quot;KDE TeaTime Logo&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;For a few weeks now 3 other KDE hackers and I have been doing a videocast/podcast/show/thing about KDE. It is a completely unprofessional unprepared amateur show where we basically talk about a different topic every week without having any script, we say things as we think them. it Doesn't matter if they are politically correct or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main motivation for having this show is to open a door to the insides of KDE. This door is open both ways so the communication should and must be from Developers to Users and the other way around, so please participate !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some urls of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Youtube channel&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/user/kdeteatime&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Facebook page&quot; href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/KdeTeaTime&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Google Plus page&quot; href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/116663776176275422594/posts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Plus page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;And of course #kdeteatime in both &lt;a title=&quot;Identi.ca link&quot; href=&quot;http://identi.ca/kdeteatime&quot;&gt;identi.ca&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&quot;kdeteatime twitter&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kdeteatime&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We are looking for all kind of participation, just to mention a few from the top of my head:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave feedback so we can improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask questions of any kind!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose topics for future teatimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose people to interview (and questions for these people)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatever you can think of :p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We usually do the shows every &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;16:00&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;CET&lt;/strong&gt; but in anycase check the latest news and dates in our &lt;strong&gt;social sites&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;So, join us and have a good time!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/meet-the-kde-teatime/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/meet-the-kde-teatime/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Workspaces gain MTP support</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know MTP stands for &quot;Media Transfer Protocol&quot;, having support for it has become really important because since Android 4.0 it is a requirement in order to manage files in any Android device, even though MTP has been here for years and other products offer support for it lilke the Nokia N9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to have MTP support we needed a &quot;kio-slave&quot;, which has been developed by Philipp Schmidt, and then modify some parts of our workspaces (dolphin, kdelibs and notifier) to integrate the MTP devices as if they were just regular massive storage (pen drives).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, small screencast showing how well it works:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/50477500&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/50477500&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vimeo link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download video&quot; href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/50477500/download?t=1349097958&amp;amp;v=120172964&amp;amp;s=6a6aa6106331f651660e1abc23356019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Direct link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to install?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;To have basic support for MTP you have to install &quot;kio-mtp&quot;, executing the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;git clone http://anongit.kde.org/kio-mtp&lt;br /&gt;
mkdir kio-mtp/build&lt;br /&gt;
cd kio-mtp/build&lt;br /&gt;
cmake ../ -DCMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX=/usr -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=Debugfull #(THIS MAY BE DIFFERENT)&lt;br /&gt;
make install&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or simply ask your distribution to package it :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Workspaces integration, I expect to get the patches in for 4.9.2 and 4.10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/workspaces-gain-mtp-support/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/workspaces-gain-mtp-support/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Extra-mile in hot-plug device handling</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Fixing mtp support for various pieces of the workspace I realized a small paper-cut I could do to improve the experience when handling external devices such pendrive or usb hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper cut is quite simple, before these patches we were using the &quot;device description&quot; for all devices, which make sense for devices always plugged into the computer for example the normal Hard Drive where your operating system is usually installed, but it doesn't make sense for removable devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will understand this better and quicker with the following screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/before.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot before changes&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/before_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Showing screenshot before changes&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and after &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/after.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot after changes&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/after_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot after changes&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patches are under review, if everything goes ok and I'm not breaking anything (little bit concerned about freeBSD support) will backport this to 4.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheerz !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/extra-mile-device-handling/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/extra-mile-device-handling/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>WebAccounts, making social/cloud easier</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This blogpost was written 2 months ago, mind that !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, for the last months I have been working on BlueSystems, one of my main projects has been creating a working prototype of &quot;WebAccounts&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is WebAccounts?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;It is a centralize place where both, users and applications can configure accounts related to various social/cloud services such twitter, identi.ca, google, facebook, dropbox, owncloud, ftp servers...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is it done?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;We have implemented a KCM (module within System Settings) that allows the user to configure a set of accounts (at the moment Google, Facebook, Owncloud and runnersID), once the account is configured you can enable a few services for each account, for example for Google you can enable: email, calendar, contacts, tasks and chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the only integration is from within WebAccounts towards the already existing subsystems such akonadi or telepathy. In the future will be those projects the ones providing plugins and asking WebAccounts for credentials and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it really worth it?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;In Akademy-es 2012 we presented the project to the audience there. One of the points I added in the slide was the amount of steps needed to configure a Google account right now and how many steps were needed to do it in WebAccounts. I don't remember the exact number but it was something like 25 to 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Places where to configure a Google account right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the account to Telepathy (one wizard, add credentials)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the KMail wizard to add the account (credentials asked again)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure Contact  (again add the same credentials)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure Calendar, select the account added when Contact was added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure Tasks, can be done in the same step of Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With WebAcounts this would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &quot;Add Google account&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce credentials (only once)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select all services (selected by default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the amount of steps has been reduced drastically actually bringing the possibility of integrating these kind of accounts in the workspace in an easy and clean way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it looks like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that this is a prototype! I expect the real version to look way nicer !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;WebAccounts first GUI&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;WebAccounts first GUI&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;125&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Google wizard&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts1_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google wizard&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;125&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts2_small.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Services all checked&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/webaccounts2_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;All services checked&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;126&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how it works?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Choose 1080 quality for better video)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/49618818&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/49618818&quot;&gt;Vimeo link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/49618818/download?t=1347908606&amp;v=117908346&amp;s=c7f4bb2323b727387d94c44067990dfe&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big part of WebAcounts future is going to be discussed at Akademy2012, where I hope to trace a roadmap together with the rest of people interested on it so we can push this concept further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/webaccounts-making-socialcloud-easier/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/webaccounts-making-socialcloud-easier/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Desktop, Desktop and Desktop, Sprint in Pineda de Mar (Barcelona)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, excuse the super late release of this post, I have been super busy up to the point where I couldn't use 15min to spellcheck this post, now I had to adapt it a little bit, change times etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 11jun to 18jun we had an amazing sprint in a small town near Barcelona called Pineda de Mar. This sprint was organized to gather all the developers highly motivated in move the &lt;strong&gt;Desktop &lt;/strong&gt;forward, including those working in areas not strictly related to what the user sees or not strictly known as part of the desktop. We had a week of fun and work lead (as usual :p) by Kevin Ottens.&lt;br /&gt;
We had endless discussions about our weak and strong spots , hacked a little bit (some more than others), played table tennis (Yay for the Southern European team vs the British Empire), and enjoyed good quality food done mostly by Dario Freddi (let the italians cook we say) though more people worked in the kitched to prepare delicious disesh (Kevin, Sebas, Clemens, Marco Martin, Lluis Eskerda...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to describe what the environment of a sprint is like, just imagine that you are with your best friends a whole week doing what you love only stopping for eating and having fun. In this case KDE is the people and what we love is our software, full week non-distractions equals super productivity of all kinds. It is hard to summarize the whole week, but these are my personal highlights of the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost everybody attending the sprint would like shorter and more dynamic releases (à la chrome or kernel).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everybody agrees that we must be careful when modifying the Desktop, we don't want to make it worst !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common agreement that we have to start looking for alternative to the current windows 95 paradigm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our current notifications suck and we know how to fix'em (&lt;a href=&quot;http://drfav.wordpress.com/2012/07/19/the-notifications-issue-part-1-the-problem/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://drfav.wordpress.com/2012/07/31/the-notifications-issue-part-2-the-status/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/Project_Elegance/Notification_Study&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual desktop are a thing from the past in its current state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activities are a super awesome concept, yet we are nowhere close to make them appealing in the desktop (as they are in the tablet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge about Plasma terminology was shared and kind of agreed on (did you know that Plasma Active is about all form factors? yes! that includes the desktop !)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need better PulseAudio support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need a better screen support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of stuff to clean and polish! papercut program by Agateau on the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lot of people using icontask (this is more of a personal note :p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAccounts is supermegaultraimportant, we need it now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We want KTp or even better &quot;KPeople&quot; everywhere, it will become one of our new pilars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this list (I hope quite close to the reality) you can see more or less the feeling of the Desktop developers, and especially that it is alive in all senses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/beach.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Pineda de Mar Beach&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/beach_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pineda de Mar Beach&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/house_view.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;House view&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/house_view_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;House view&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/house_view.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Outside having a chat&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/outside_chatting_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Outside having a chat&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/food.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;First wave of food&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/food_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First wave of food&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/talking_hackingzone.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Hacking zone&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/talking_hackingzone_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hacking zone&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/kitchen.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/kitchen_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/table_tennis.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Table Tennis&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/table_tennis_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Table Tennis&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/kanban.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Kanban everywhere&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/kanban_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kanban everywhere&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/group_photo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Group Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/group_photo_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Group Photo&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos taken by Martin Klapetek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you could see a glimpse of how intense a sprint is lived and how useful they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bye !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/desktop-desktop-and-desktop-sprint-in-pineda-de-mar-barcelona/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/desktop-desktop-and-desktop-sprint-in-pineda-de-mar-barcelona/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Samba-mounter, quick fix for a larger problem</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time, years ago when computer users only needed to keep all their files in one place, and occasionally make some backup to a CD or DVD. Then the mp3 players appeared and those users had to copy the music from the computer to the player usually via USB, that's all we needed we thought... well we were wrong :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of devices we have and we &lt;strong&gt;use &lt;/strong&gt;is increasing and so does the amount of data we manage, some may think that a regular non geek user has few files but if you take a closer look you will see that the average user actually has hundreds of pictures, hundreds of sounds, hundreds of films, dozens of documents... So we have to ask ourselves a question: Can we continue with the model of copying that data around? the answer is &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motivated by that need users are starting to setup a central computer or a device such a NAS with the only propose of  storing data and make it available to any device that may need it such: cell phones, players, ebook readers, tv's, other computers etc. Some times that central place is not even a computer dedicated to do that job but instead the daily used computer, I'm specifically thinking on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file transfer are usually done with protocols such nfs, webdav, ftp or samba being this last the most common at least in commercial devices. The need for supporting this is clear as users of these systems increase, so how well do we support Samba?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had a kick ass technology called KIO for years, I believe it was developed in KDE 2 and basically it allows to use remote files as if they were local,  meaning that you can use files in an ftp for example without having to use any special programs for it. Even with KIO, we have identify some issues that need to be solved before we can say that our remote file support has no gaps, for example streaming or support for applications not supporting KIO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's say for example that we have a collection of music in a NAS device and they are shared through Samba, can we reproduce them using any KDE application? or better, can we &lt;strong&gt;stream&lt;/strong&gt; and reproduce them? the answer is sadly &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a series of technical problems that we have to fix to make KDE software fully capable of streaming music, I won't bother you with technical details just know that actions are being taken to fix this situation and because of KIO we should be able to stream music on applications that use it in no time hopefully in 4.9.0 or 4.9.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about applications not using KIO, is there any way for making them work ? short answer is it depends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are technical mechanisms for making Samba remote files look like local for all applications, for example for this protocol we have cifs, smbnetfs and fusesmb. According to the tests we performed only cifs is fast enough to provide a good experience but still you usually need to know some command or edit a file you are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; supposed to modify in order to have a good experience so it is not a solution by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are designing a solution that will make KIO available to any application, but that will take months of developing and testing  and we needed something fast, something to include in Netrunner 4.2 Dryland SE... So we created samba-mounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samba-mounter is a small piece of code that makes easy the usage of cifs, improving the experience of those who need to access files shared through samba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the following video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/samba-mounter.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/samba-mounter.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the code from here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://quickgit.kde.org/index.php?p=scratch/afiestas/samba-mounter.git&quot;&gt;http://quickgit.kde.org/index.php?p=scratch/afiestas/samba-mounter.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect to write a blog post explaining the long-term solution in the following weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/samba-mounter-quick-fix-for-a-larger-problem/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/samba-mounter-quick-fix-for-a-larger-problem/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Akademy-es 2012, makes everything worth it</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Most of you know me because of all the work I do on KDE in form of code: Kamoso, BlueDevil, Solid... It is the stuff I put on my blog so if you know my involvement in KDE because of my blog it is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides writing code, I'm starting to be involved in other areas all across our community, one of them is KDE-España.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE-España is the legal representation of KDE in Spain, you can consider it as a sister of KDE e.V but only for the local community. One of the activities we do is the Akademy-es, a gathering of users and developers that happens every year in a different city of the country, so far we have had: Barcelona, Saragossa, Coruña, Bilbao, Barcelona, Saragossa (again :p) and sure more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may think these events are less important than writing software and that I shouldn't waste my time there. I say you are &lt;strong&gt;wrong &lt;/strong&gt;and that at least they are equally important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a personal note, for me it is becoming one of the events I wait the entire year to attend even if it is only to see the group of friends I only see in that conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'd like to encourage you to organize Akademy's or smaller events on whatever city/country you live in, building a strong local community is crucial for keeping this global ship alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/group_picture.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;Akademy-es 2012 Group Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/group_picture_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Can't wit for Akademy-es 2013 :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/akademy-es-2012-makes-everything-worth-it/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/akademy-es-2012-makes-everything-worth-it/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Joining the Blue</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I planned to announce this when it happened but got stuck with travels and work so it got delayed a bit (2 months :p).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad to say that I will be sponsored by Blue Systems to work on various parts of the Workspace, so far we have defined two areas of work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve transparent file browsing (KIO) and make it available to all applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve web and online services integration into the Workspace, by adding a single point of configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these two months I have been working already on those areas making the first releases that will be included in the  upcoming netrunner version (4.2 Dryland SE). Both releases are designed to be a first stone of a much complete solution on which I will be working on at least  for the following 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who may be wondering, this changes nothing regarding my other KDE implications, I'm going to continue working on BlueDevil (bluetooth) and libsolid and other projects I'm cooking while others sleep :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's keep rocking !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;Blue system  logo&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/blue-systems-logo300.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;113&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/joining-the-blue/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/joining-the-blue/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>One less thing that can put your laptop in danger</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago it almost happened to me. It was horrible. I was traumatized. I wonder, how can that happend in 2011? why me? why to my laptop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a worm afternoon in Madrid, the meeting I attended was so intensive I didn't get to login into the KDE Plasma Workspace session but instead I let the laptop on the KDM login page. Once the session finished I closed my laptop and put it in my bag full of battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure about the amount of time, but probably between 3 to 4 hours later I arrived home, opened my backpack and there it was, I found my laptop burning, hot as hell I even had to grab a cloth to open the lid and move the laptop to some place cool. From that day my new battery went form 98% of capacity to 90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night, I  sent an email to some KDE mailist asking for this issue, until today nothing has been done to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want anybody to pass from the same I went through, that's why now with lightdm-kde the computer will suspend if the lid is closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next thing I want to do is show the battery remaining somewhere and suspend the computer after 2 minutes of idle time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, lightdm-kde will have great power management support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/one-less-thing-that-can-put-your-laptop-in-danger/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/one-less-thing-that-can-put-your-laptop-in-danger/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.7, 1.1.4, 1.2.3 and 1.3-rc2 bug fixing frenezy !</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I have had the energy and the time to hunt the damn crashes that have been affecting BlueDevil since the beginning, fixing them has been relatively easy, be able to reproduce them instead has been quite time exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I fixed all those damn crashes I proceeded to do bug triage and managed to fix all of the confirmed bugs, or said in another way BlueDevil is virtually bug free &lt;a title=&quot;Bug list of BlueDevil&quot; href=&quot;http://goo.gl/WIeTz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bug list&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still a &lt;a title=&quot;iPhone bug 1&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=285637&quot;&gt;couple &lt;/a&gt;of bugs with &lt;a title=&quot;iPhone bug 2&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=287195&quot;&gt;iPhones&lt;/a&gt;, but I will need one of those to be able to confirm and fix the issues. Any donation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changelog looks as follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes for 1.0.7, 1.1.4, 1.2.3 and 1.3-rc2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=298633&quot;&gt;298633&lt;/a&gt; // Crash in kded daemon (ObexFtp module)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=279911&quot;&gt;279911&lt;/a&gt; // Crash after receiving a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=297785&quot;&gt;297785&lt;/a&gt; //Not confirmed if it is fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated pin databse for more automatic experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes for 1.1.4. 1.2.3 and 1.3-rc2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=286466&quot;&gt;286466&lt;/a&gt; // Be able to pair WiiMotes (needs BlueZ 4.96)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=276911&quot;&gt;276911&lt;/a&gt; // Pairing Keyboards with SSPairing (Bluetooth 2.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=291708&quot;&gt;291708&lt;/a&gt; // Now we show again the small overlay icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes only for 1.3-rc2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=284052&quot;&gt;284052&lt;/a&gt; // Nasty crash every time adapter is unplugged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can proceed and create new bugs by continuing with BlueDevil 2.0 and Screen Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/libbluedevil/1.9.2/src/libbluedevil-1.9.2.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;libbluedevil 1.9.2&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;md5sum: b492db1825b239e5185c543badb21c26&lt;br /&gt;
sha256sum: 00d56fc671fecda1e60aa8231ba167f11002148098d6510df0a409d19e840d59&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/bluedevil/1.0.7/src/bluedevil-1.0.7.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bluedevil 1.0.7&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;md5sum: 27e48595679bac72f6ea0d1f496ce524&lt;br /&gt;
sha256sum: 2294f921de0a2920dbfe8b3f824abd8b7d468da71a8bce5e4575be311bc0af65&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/bluedevil/1.1.4/src/bluedevil-1.1.4.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bluedevil 1.1.4&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;md5sum: b485e0a710146536362cd607bcc3a418&lt;br /&gt;
sha256sum: c0bab0d6a505dbe96d3f6acaad8bdf4aea4de84c342e0e6e59b47e0d5bcba6d6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/bluedevil/1.2.3/src/bluedevil-1.2.3.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bluedevil 1.2.3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;md5sum: e792576d34956d27cd0c3eb3c81a5923&lt;br /&gt;
sha256sum: 7744e0544d27960f21073cf4b48ba865162a2643b7e33f7f21fff43705b4e624&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/unstable/bluedevil/1.3-rc2/src/bluedevil-1.3-rc2.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bluedevil 1.3-rc2&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;md5sum: 20452c528ab04c0551f3d8bfc5075c4b&lt;br /&gt;
sha256sum: db6735d5a66634ce5d761c70df4ad7c4f39295ac4a6f9b59bcc25777dc720dd5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-7-1-1-4-1-2-3-and-1-3-rc2-bug-fixing-frenezy/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-7-1-1-4-1-2-3-and-1-3-rc2-bug-fixing-frenezy/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Plasma Active 3 sprint</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I attended to the PA3 sprint in Darmstadt, as always I enjoyed a few days with my friends not only working but also taking beers, going dinner etc. I have had a really good time there as I always do when KDE is in the formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know this is the first PA sprint where a lot of community members external to the project attended, this is really great for opening the project to other areas of KDE, such Solid or KDEdu.  My work focus were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting to know the inside of the project&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Every project structure is different even between close projects such PowerDevil and BlueDevil. In the case of PA there are a few big differences that have to be taken into account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people working on it are employed by companies (and most of them work on it full time).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PA should be always ready for release, no unstable or untested stuff allowed in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong focus on well designed and usable interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything QML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a strong and shared Vision behind it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; It is important that you agree with the rules of the game before you start to play it, I find PA a really good example of how a professional project can be done together with the community without sacrificing anything. I agree with this rules so I will play this game :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Plan how Screen Management will be implemented in PA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As some of you may know, I'm currently working on a new implementation of Screen Management, even though I'm really delayed on the original schedule the project is not abandoned and I hope to make PA one of the first use cases for it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
When Thomas Pfeiffer and I started to look at how we can implement Screen Management into PA we quickly identify one valid use case:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
A user is reviewing a set of pictures on its Tablet, at some points he decides to plug its tablet in the TV and watch them in there. Once the TV is plugged the pictures are shown in both screens so the user can use the tablet to control the application while watching the images in the TV.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
A user just bought a movie via Bodega, he wants to play it in its big TV. In this case the controls of the movies will be in the Tablet while the movie itself will be reproduced at the screen.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
A user connects the Tablet into a projector and intends to do a presentation using Calligra Active. The controls of the presentation (Notes, countdown, thumbnails) will be shown at the tablet while the Slides will be shown at the projector.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
As you can see it makes only sense to do something with the external screen if, and only if there is an application that will make use of it, or said in another way we discarded to show the shell into the external screen.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Plan how bluetooth should be implemented in PA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As Thomas and I did with Screen Management, we took a look at how Bluetooth should be integrated with PA. Some parts of it can be already used and other parts need a nice QML interface. Following some conclusions we reached:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don't want a Wizard, it is not needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need a Share Like Connect plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need a PA system settings panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device configuration should be within the PA system settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;When doing the analysis of how to implement Bluetooth into PA I realized mistakes done in the Desktop (I have been realizing those mistakes for quite some time now). I will implement them in a future BlueDevil 2.0 version.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Social / Sharing / shiny stuff in KDE software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Sharing, social, cloud, buzzwords all over that's true but nonetheless important. There are different efforts going on in KDE to make this happen, and make it quick. We had a super interesting BoF about all things that needs to done to make Social/Sharing/Cloud a natural thing in KDE software, it should be as natural as creating a file or as launching an application.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;List of points I remember:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share/Like/Connect for the desktop must happen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a centralized place for Sharing is important (probably in the shell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need a centralized place to store Web/Online account information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to have a shared platform for streams (twitter, identi.ca, facebook...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having libkpeople finished is crucial, we must have unified personas to work with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I will probably be working on the first point, but we will see about that later.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Finally, a mandatory picture took by Martin K.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;PA attendees working&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/pa3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PA attendees working&quot; width=&quot;637&quot; height=&quot;424&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This post was written on Match 14, information can be outdated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/plasma-active-3-sprint/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/plasma-active-3-sprint/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>AppMenu Runner, meet the KDE's HUD</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Mark Shuttleworth &lt;a title=&quot;Mark's announcement&quot; href=&quot;http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/939&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced the HUD menu,&lt;/a&gt; a  Unity dialog that lets you trigger menu actions in the focused application like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look for bookmarks,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change your IM status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;execute an action contained in the menu bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This kind of features as well of how they are executed may sound familiar to you dear Plasma Worksapce user... Exactly! I'm referring to our beloved &lt;a title=&quot;KRunner's userbase page&quot; href=&quot;http://userbase.kde.org/Plasma/Krunner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KRunner&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRunner can do a lot of stuff in both global and active application scope (though it tends to offer more global features) , just to mention a few: Math, Bookmarks, Files, Calendar, Contacts, Emails, Devices, Change IM Status, Recent documents...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I'm glad to see Unity going into this direction since it is something that we (KDE Community) have believe in for years, so having Canonical and its designer team walking into the same direction may indicate that we are not wrong or at least we are not the only ones mistaken :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite KRunner being able to do a lot of things it couldn't do something the HUD does, execute actions contained in the menu. No less than 7 months ago I did my first attempt on achieve exactly that and of course &lt;a title=&quot;My first attempt&quot; href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/improving-kde-applications-help-menu-actions-lookup/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I blogged about it&lt;/a&gt;. I didn't continue with the effort mainly because: kdelibs was frozen, it worked only for KDE applications, it worked only if the menu bar was shown within the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching the HUD video I got inspired and motivated to create a Runner which will use the same technology as HUD (and the oxygen-appmenu or the plasma-menubar plasmoid) to look and execute menu bar actions, this is the result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/9lGVy6GRbOc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KDE's appMenu Runner&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/appMenuRunner.ogv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Direct link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things to work on but I hope to put this in KDE Plasma Worksapce 4.9 if the Plasma teams like it of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;git://anongit.kde.org/scratch/afiestas/appmenu.git&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubuntu packages are WIP&lt;br /&gt;
Would be nice if somebody can write a manual of how to setup appmenu in Qt and maybe other toolkits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/appmenu-runner-meet-the-kde-hud/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/appmenu-runner-meet-the-kde-hud/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Looking forward to 2012</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm sure 2012 is going to be an amazing year for Free Software and of course for the KDE community, a lot is happening within our community and we have just started the year ! Just to mention a few from the top of my mind: Calligra getting closer, Plasma Active2, 4.8 release, Frameworks 5, OwnCloud 3, Spark... I can go on for a while :) As every six month or so, here is the list of what I'm planing to work on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppMenu KRunner (you will see it tomorrow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/Solid/Projects/DisplayManagement/Design&quot;&gt;new RandR supoprt &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libsolid in Frameworks5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlueDevil 3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso-QML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community work on Solid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community work on KDE-España&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to get all finished before &lt;a href=&quot;http://akademy.kde.org/&quot;&gt;Akademy-2012&lt;/a&gt; and with a little bit of luck be able to work on more stuff. I promise, next post will be my &quot;usual&quot; post with pictures and videos :P!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/looking-forward-to-2012/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/looking-forward-to-2012/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Quick status update:</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! long time no see :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been moving from Madrid to BCN, cities which are around 650km away and that is keeping me busy because I can't neglect work time for doing it and even if I could the process put pressure into your head so you spend more time procrastinating than before. Nevertheless the moving is almost complete and I'm going to be using more and more time in KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what I'm going to use my KDE time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish 1.3 release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug triage, fix'em all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a known bug in Wizard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamoso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup an environment where I can work with latest camerabin2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish Kamoso port to camerabin2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;libsolid&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that MTP devices work well in KDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may include write a MTP kio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen Management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally start to push code into a scratch repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having something functional by 4.8 release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think I'm going to focus in the latest (Screen Management) because is the one most people is waiting for and I've failed to deliver in a reasonable time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This is it for now, see you!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/quick-status-update/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/quick-status-update/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.6, 1.1.3, 1.2.2 and 1.3-rc1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I proposed myself to clean the BlueDevil's &lt;a title=&quot;BlueDevil bug list&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?cmdtype=dorem&amp;amp;remaction=run&amp;amp;namedcmd=bluetooth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bug list&lt;/a&gt;, at the beginning of the weekend the list had 42 bugs (including wishes), at this moment it has 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started the bug triage process, I realize that we had too much crashes so I decided to sit down and fix'em all, well I think I did and because of that we're releasing new versions for each branch including a new one (1.3) which is the only one that includes a huge change in the KDE Daemon that fixes a bunch of crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed in 1.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=270064&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;270064&lt;/a&gt;: Crash in bluedevil-wizard while broswing a device in dolpin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=280908&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;280908&lt;/a&gt;: Crash in bluetooth input helper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=282280&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;282280&lt;/a&gt;: Crash upon removing bluetooth device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=269814&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;269814&lt;/a&gt;: kde service krashed on blueman-manager start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=271427&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;271427&lt;/a&gt;: bluedevil crash renaming a disapeared device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=277992&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;277992&lt;/a&gt;: Removed mouse from device list in KCM while using the connection wizard crashed the KCM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=273144&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;273144&lt;/a&gt;: Crash after recieve a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=274772&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;274772&lt;/a&gt;: Cancelling transfer from mobile phone results in technical error message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed pairing when the PIN is asked from outside (this happened only some times)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Fixes only affecting 1.1 adn 1.2:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=272230&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;272230&lt;/a&gt;: Bluedevil KCM crashed when editing details of device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=281420&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;281420&lt;/a&gt;: Bluetooth Wizard Crash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Fixed only in 1.3:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed 4 crashes in KDE Daemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Tarballs can be download from &lt;a title=&quot;Stable1.0.6 tarball&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.6/src/bluedevil-1.0.6.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.0&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&quot;Stable 1.1.3 release&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.1.3/src/bluedevil-1.1.3.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&quot;Stable 1.2.2&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.2.2/src/bluedevil-1.0.6.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&quot;Unstable 1.3-rc1&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=unstable/bluedevil/1.3-rc1/src/bluedevil-1.3-rc1.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-6-1-1-3-1-2-2-and-1-3-rc1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-6-1-1-3-1-2-2-and-1-3-rc1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.1.2 and 1.2.1 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Though we released the 1.2 version a while ago we decided to delay the announcement since there were some annoying bugs that now, thanks to the testing performed by the kubuntu community are fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant posts about BlueDevil 1.2 (with videos and pictures  :p):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-rc1-released/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BlueDevil 1.2 RC1 released (changelog here)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-support-for-dun-and-panu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Support for DUN and PANU (use device as modem)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-kio_bluetooth-configured-and-discovered-devices/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kio_bluetooth improved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;For 1.1 branch there is only one fix that solve an annoying behavior when the wizard is invoked with pre-selected address and uuid (basically it was working behaving poorly, now it works well).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This is it for now, next thing to do is releasing 1.3 (aka the release that will fix all known crashes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;You can download them &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.1.2/src/bluedevil-1.1.2.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (1.1.2) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.2.1/src/bluedevil-1.2.1.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (1.2.1)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I hope you enjoy them !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Note: I forgot to public this post so the releases are actually a few weeks old, and we're about to release new ones in a few days :p&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-2-and-1-2-1-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-2-and-1-2-1-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Usability at Forge 2011</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most important thing that is happening in Forge 2011 is the amount of work we're doing related to usability, focusing all our efforts in tree projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Places View&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;In all three of them we used more or less the same methodology and because of that we have been able to reuse some work we did for Network Management into the rest of the projects; Let me introduce you to Penny and Amy.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;After we defined the vision of Network Management (basically how and in what we think NM should help users) we needed to decide the kind of users we're targeting, for doing that we defined two personas each in one corner case, one is  computer science profesional and the other one is only interested in watching lolcats :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Penny's full profile&quot; href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/NetworkManagement#Persona_2:_Penny&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Penny&lt;/a&gt;: She is only interested in &quot;being&quot; online not into &quot;get&quot; online, meaning that she wants stuff to work out of the box or at least without bothering her alot.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Amy's full profile&quot; href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/NetworkManagement#Persona_1:_Amy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amy&lt;/a&gt;: She is a sysadmin, she wants to be able to configure all the possible options out there .&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;(Click on the name to read the full persona description).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;So,  once we got our two personas defined and the main target selected (Penny) the next step was to list a few &lt;a title=&quot;Places list on NM usability&quot; href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/NetworkManagement#Places&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;places&lt;/a&gt; where each persona will use Network Management, for example: &quot;Penny's home, train, park...&quot;. Finally we went through all possibilities imagining what our personas will &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/NetworkManagement#Goals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;want to do&lt;/a&gt; in that location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The funny thing about this is that we end up thinking like our personas will do, trying to make our best so Penny will be happy while Amy won't be bothered. And you want to know another funny thing? we discovered that by making Penny's life easier we were making Amy's easier as well, no matter if Amy is an &quot;advanced user&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't talk by others, but I will think as Penny from now on when I'm designing workspace stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Network Management personas&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/personas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/usability-at-forge-2011/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/usability-at-forge-2011/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Forge 2011, day 1 !</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally the Solid sprint 2011 (kown as Forge) has started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day has been a little weird since sadly some metalworkers were not able to make it :/ but we had to start so, this being a &quot;Ervin driven sprint&quot; we started creating a kanban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That took us a few hours, good thing is that now all we have in front of us is hacking, thats it!! 3 days of non-stop hacking :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At dinner time our usability messiah arrived, showing us the light in how to do an &quot;user centred development&quot; model, I will blog about it if nobody else does :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm arriving at the office so the rest of the blog entry will have to wait until later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Force 2011 Kanban &quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/kanban.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kanban from Force 2011&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Hacking !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ps: Donations of high quality Sticky notes are welcomed :p&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/forge-2011-day-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/forge-2011-day-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Two annoying bugs fixed in KDirWatch and kuiserver</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick announce for the interested parties (distributions and advanced users).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I pushed a couple of fixes that fix annoying bugs and because of that I belive that you may want to backport them to 4.6.5 or even to 4.7.1 if you don't want or you can't wait until 4.7.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Folder contents are not refreshing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happens only when using a kernel with two digits uname such 3.0-ARCH for example, commit to backport is:  kdelibs &lt;em&gt;7df5a79fb9f09e4a4a80cd541cc478b5fa6df00f&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty jobs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some times jobs are shown empty though the job itself is working fine, this happen in a random situation depending on the system load etc, it was no easily reproducible but thanks to my slow and lovely computer I could then I fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commits to backport are two in kde-runtime: &lt;em&gt;329a4fe6fe7b8a9262d5ef7fefba255e9c29fade&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;d769c74a5cab576e124666174a0b2bc5e2af8cde&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two fixes will be released with 4.7.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/two-annoying-bugs-fixed-in-kdirwatch-and-kuiserver/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/two-annoying-bugs-fixed-in-kdirwatch-and-kuiserver/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Next in BlueDevil</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These last tree weeks have been crazy, apart from being busy sorting things out where I work, I have been doing an strict diet + sport to see if I can get rid of my extra weight, so far I'm not less Àlex than I was tree weeks ago, exactly 10Kg less (22 pounds says google...). Well stop of talking about myself, let's talk about BlueDevil!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil 1.2:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Probably tomorrow we will be releasing the 1.2 version, since we released RC1/2 we have good good feedback, no new bugs seems to be reported so we think that we're good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil 1.3:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;This version was not in the plan, but after starting to work in the 2.0 version we found something we think that have to be &quot;backported&quot; to the 1.X branch. Basically more than a year ago when we started to work in the new stack, we found ourselves in a situation where the use of a thread  seemed correct and needed, so we use it. Now after a year 100% of the crash reports we get apparently came from that thread and so far we have not been able to find a solution since the crash is kinda random... I can't reproduce it so I can't fix it basically. Well the good news are that we found a way of removing that thread so in theory after this change we will be virtually crash free, yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to summarize: The 1.3 version will have only one change, which is the removal of the &quot;AgentListener&quot; thread in the BlueDevilDaemon (kded).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil 2.0:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;This is the next big version of BlueDevil, don't worry we won't be breaking anything :) Currently we're using obex-data-server for a few things such receiving files, the problem is that it is almost un-maintained for example &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.muiline.com/view.php?id=647&quot;&gt;this bug&lt;/a&gt; which is quite critical for kio_oebxftp has not been touched though I pinged the author via bugtrack and email. But not worry, the BlueZ community has been working in a replacement for months or even years it is called obexd. We are already using obexd for sending files and so far it is working great so the idea is to port everythiing that uses obex-data-server to obexd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one problem though, obexd is not done by desktop in mind so we will have to do some patching there in order to add the needed settings we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dates, dates, dates, everybody love dates...  this is the non-strict non-hard schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2: Tomorrow&lt;br /&gt;
1.3: Next Friday&lt;br /&gt;
2.0: By the end of the month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be focusing myself in BlueDevil the entire month, the sooner we finish these changes the sooner we can work in other stuff, personally I will work in KRandR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/next-in-bluedevil/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/next-in-bluedevil/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.2 RC1 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of development the Solid team is proud to announce the first release candidate of BlueDevil 1.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action Plugins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for DUN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for PANU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few description changed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the Category mess we had in the .desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kio_bluetooth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show known devices first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform discovery in the background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the mimetype mess we had&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will work when started without Bluetooth activated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wizard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added another OUI for Apple Wireless Mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto select Mouse's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to use Return or Enter to introduce PIN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monolithic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Configure icon on the configure option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KCM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use KMessageWidget if compiled against 4.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things to test:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Please, focus the testing in kio_bluetooth since it has been almost rewritten&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=unstable/bluedevil/1.2-rc1/src/bluedevil-1.2-rc1.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=unstable/bluedevil/1.2-rc1/src/bluedevil-1.2-rc1.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We hope you enjoy it and cheers from Barajas airport (Madrid) destination Berlin via Munich.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-rc1-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-rc1-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Smart Folders in KDE Workspace</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few days ago I was talking with an apple fanboy friend of mine who used to be KDE user before being abducted by the i* family of products (he started with an iPhone, he ended with i*Everything...). Anyway he is still using KDE from time to time so I asked him what is the feature he misses most when he is using KDE, the answer as you may gest was &quot;Smart Folders&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Apple a smart folder is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Smart Folders, you can organize files by what they have in common, instead of by their location on your disk. Because they use Spotlight, Smart Folders can organize files by their contents, as well by attributes that describe those contents and how they were created. For example, you can create one Smart Folder with all your spreadsheets, another with the documents you modified today, and another with the presentations that mention a specific project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you know what? we already have this and we've had this for a few releases, let me show you proof:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/magic_folder.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/magic_folder.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as an extra:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/magic_folder2.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/magic_folder2.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as you can see we're only lacking a few GUI pieces to complete the puzzle, any takers? would be awesome to have this for 4.8 don't you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/smart-folders-in-kde-workspace/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/smart-folders-in-kde-workspace/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>[BlueDevil 1.2] Support for DUN and PANU</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody seems to have found the eastergg.. so I won't be giving away the N950 I wanted to... (ah, I forgot to say that? xD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the easteregg was a small Network icon showing up in Dolphin at 03:02 :) which in BlueDevil 1.2 will allow you to launch the DUN or PANU configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm writing this post, only DUN support is implemented since I don't have a device that support PANU, but don't worry as I say in the following video support for PANU will be implemented in a few days, it is just a couple string replaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandatory video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/network.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/network.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like it, and see you in the next blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-support-for-dun-and-panu/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-support-for-dun-and-panu/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>[BlueDevil 1.2] kio_bluetooth configured and discovered devices</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After releasing stable versions (boooring) there is nothing better than publish new features, and it gets even better when those features are between the most requested/wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feature I'm going to introduce may sound kinda useless for some people, but in all KDE software we offer different ways of doing things, so you can find which way integates better with your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In BlueDevil 1.0 and 1.1 when you use the kio_bluetooth (bluetooh:// in your browser), what it did was start a bluetooth discovery, meaning that the only devices going to appear into the file browser were those who had the visible mode activated. This behavior is totally counterproductive since you have to: wait 10 seconds until the scan ends and/or turn on the visibility in your device. Well you won't have to do this anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the first thing that is shown in kio_bluetooth are the configured devices allowing you to quickly select one device, at the same time a discovery is perform in the background so new devices will appear when found (and not when the 10seconds scan ends).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A picture say more than thousand words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/kio_bluetoth12.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Kio Bluetooth on steroids&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/kio_bluetoth12.png&quot; alt=&quot;kio_bluetooth discovered and configured devices&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the mandatory video, watch it careful! I've put an Easter egg on it which shows about what I'm going to talk tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/kio_bluetooth.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/kio_bluetooth.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya and remember, this feature is going to be available in BlueDevil 1.2, to be released in 4/6 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-kio_bluetooth-configured-and-discovered-devices/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-2-kio_bluetooth-configured-and-discovered-devices/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.5 and 1.1.1 released!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Between all the hard work we're doing within the Solid community (Networking, XRandR, Power Management...) we always find time to release patch releases which usually fix small issues and help to ease the waiting until the next big release is done.  Now it is time for BlueDevil to have some patch releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil 1.0.5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug: 277451&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bahaviors in kio_obexftp while copying files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the file size and the speed in the file transfer (in kio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start/Quit bluedevil-monolithic in online/offline mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved layout to look good in all Qt Styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge i18n improvements (fix's and more translations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;BlueDevil 1.1.1:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed  bug: 277665&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug:  277451&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug:  277878&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bahaviors in kio_obexftp while copying files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the file size and the speed in the file transfer (in kio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;One thing about 1.0.5, it is going to be the last 1.0.X version with new translations, that doesn't mean that we will stop giving support to it, thanks for our good codebase it is quite easy for us to maintain different releases, as you can see we've 3 bug fixes applied in both releases.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;If you're a distribution maintainer is quite important that you consider upgrading to this new versions, main reason? i18n!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Downloads:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.5/src/bluedevil-1.0.5.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.5/src/bluedevil-1.0.5.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;And&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.1.1/src/bluedevil-1.1.1.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.1.1/src/bluedevil-1.1.1.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-5-and-1-1-1-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-5-and-1-1-1-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Display Configuration in KDE-Workspace 4.7.1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In my way home from work, talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ereslibre.es/&quot; title=&quot;Ereslibre's blog&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ereslibre&lt;/a&gt; we concluded that would be awesome if I could fix the current &quot;KRandR&quot; code before starting to work on new one. With the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afiestas.org/an-extremely-productive-weekend-plasma-kwin-bluedevil/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;adrenaline boost&lt;/a&gt;&quot; still in my blood I sat down and started to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days of working, I'm pleased to announce that for KDE-Workspace 4.7.1 the &quot;Screen/Display/Whatever configuration&quot; has been hugely improve, all bug fix though but now it even seems to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bugs I've fixed are hard to explain with words but I'm going to try anyway:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRandRTray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Won't react on external changes (won't force its configuration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will update the menu (If you remove the VGA cable, VGA won't appear)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will show disconnected outputs as disconnected in the popup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Configuration Dialog (KCM):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Unify Output&quot; option has been added (aka you will get always the expected behavior)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview/Options will update on external changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Maybe I 'm forgetting something... but more or less that's it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;And like almost always, the mandatory video explaining the bug fixes, comparing KDE Workspace 4.6.5 and 4.7.1:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/xrandr.webm&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/xrandr.webm&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I hope you like it, and stay tuned if you're interested on &quot;XRandR&quot; support, because more is to come.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/display-configuration-in-kde-workspace-4-7-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/display-configuration-in-kde-workspace-4-7-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An extremely productive Weekend (Plasma, KWin, BlueDevil)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Is not a secret that the last few weeks (or even a month) I have been kind of unmotivated to work on KDE stuff, and that is a deal breaker to work on something you're not paid for and you do it only for the pleasure of doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the reasons why I was unmotivated (or how I like to call it, kde-depressed) are still there, last Friday after finishing 3 important projects at work I felt again the adrenalin boost that makes me hack like crazy, no matter on what, but I have to hack on something. This is how one of my most productive weekends begun :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very same Friday at night I started hacking on some work stuff, nothing I can say here (because it doesn't matter at all) but I can assure you that my partners will be happy once they know :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday, I started to hack on KDE stuff and decided that instead of developing BlueDevil or Solid I was going to fix these small details that annoy me every day, and so far I fixed everything I wanted to fix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plasma:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/101968/&quot;&gt;Panel auto-expand on XRandR events&lt;/a&gt; (probably will go into 4.7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KWin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/101969/&quot;&gt;Not let any window off screen on XRandR events&lt;/a&gt; (This will have to wait until 4.7.1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After fixing these two bugs was time to give some love to the old BlueDevil :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug triage, quite a trivial task but time consuming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=277878&quot;&gt;277878&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=277451&quot;&gt;277451&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial rewrite of kio_bluetooth (I will explain further in another post)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=245538&quot;&gt;245538&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=253810&quot;&gt;253810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=277665&quot;&gt;277665&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show only &quot;connection title&quot; in systray if there are more than one service to connect to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's for Saturday :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then today, Sunday I started the journey with some XRandR hacking, the plan to'em all is almost done and it will include a coulpe of fixes for 4.7.1 (though I'm not sure of it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaand finally another bug fix of these small annoying things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/101981/&quot;&gt;Fix notification behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now time to rest, who knows if tomorrow I will continue with this adrenaline boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/an-extremely-productive-weekend-plasma-kwin-bluedevil/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/an-extremely-productive-weekend-plasma-kwin-bluedevil/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My KDE’s priorities (for the next 6 months)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again it is time for me to organize my priorities within KDE for the next 6 months, I have had to drop a few things from the list since I'm not sure how much time Solid community and KDE-España are going to take from me since the work I will be doing there is rather not technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is my list of priorities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downstream:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downstream people are those who use our stuff to produce something else, for example: distributions, developers using our libraries, designers using our icons...&lt;br /&gt;
A few months ago, motivated with the need of giving a better support of how BlueDevil should be packaged I started to interact a lot with people working on different distributions. Because of that I was sponsored to go to the UDS and there I finally could understand more or less how a distribution works, how Kubuntu team works/thinks etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the next 6 months I will continue working with &quot;downstream&quot; focusing my efforts in organize a meeting with people from all distributions so at least we can be synchronized in the lowest common denominator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid is now the sub-community within KDE that cares about hardware. We work in quite a few areas right now like Network/Power Management, irda ...&lt;br /&gt;
I have to say that since last November we've pretty much catch up with other workspaces for example now people assume that KDE NetworkManager interface should work, and you know what? it does! Also our UDisk/UPower/UDev support is in my humble opinion excelkenet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the next 6 months, I want to see the Solid community growing and getting more projects into it, for example Printing or Input would be perfect candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamoso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamoso is a webcam application to take pictures and videos from cameras, this is what I call my &quot;Pet Project&quot;. The status of Kamoso is quite good right now, we've reach the 2.0 version which is demonstrating to be a really rock solid release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that he project is providing the basics (it is stable and you can take pictures/videos) is time for us to move to the next step. which can be summarize in one word: &lt;strong&gt;effects&lt;/strong&gt;. To get there we've defined this abstracted roadmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso 2.5: Kamoso ported to use camerabin2 (technicall stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso 3.0: Effects and maybe some QML magic :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil is the codename of the KDE's Bluetooth integration on which we've been working for a year now. Though the project may seem complete since it is fulfilling all the Bluetooth needs a normal user could have it is not perfect, or putting it in another word it is not excellent. So the target for the next 6 month will be reaching excellence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.0.5: i18n will be improved and a few bugs fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.1.1: i18n will be hugely improve, and bug fixing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2: Most changes will be on the KIO's, also the wizard will be further improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.3: Port the project totally to obexd, deprecating the support for obex-data-server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, between this versions we may work on plasma-active support, which basically means write QML interfaces around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Silk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my humble point of view, the laptop/pc is becoming a complement of two things: Our gadgets (cell phones, tablets..) and the so called &quot;Cloud&quot;. It is quite obvious that a computer without internet is only useful for those whom want to do some work on it, but for the rest of the users it would be useless. Because of that we've to accept our new role as a complement of something else and stop thinking that we're the central piece of software or that even the user care about us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE's projects are doing quite a fine job integrating with the cloud, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Akonadi supports exchange servers and of course Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE-Telepathy is near the corner bringing to the table IM integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kipi-Plugins supporting facebook/picasa/...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso supporting youtube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choqok and Plasma on microblogging...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, we're still failing on truly integrating these services into the desktop. To start fixing it here comes my proposal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need  a central place (maybe a KCM) where the user can configure her/his online accounts and we will do the rest, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I add my Google account, the KCM should offer me to auto-configure my account in: Telepathy (Chat), Akonadi (synchronize calendar, contact, rss, todo's...), Choqok (microblogging)... Also some applications like Kamoso should be able to access to that account and use it for example to upload videos to Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, some good integration with Rekonq would be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have concrete plans of when or how I will do this but almost sure it will start just as a proof of concept (I don't have time to do more).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XRandR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least here comes my new obsession: fix the overall kde-workspace XRandR support. Right now our workspace supports XRandR more or less well but it is far from being good enough for me. I will publish an entire blogspot about my plans here but bottom line: I will try to fix everything for 4.8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this is it, let's see how much I can finally accomplish and see you by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/my-kde-e2-80-99s-priorities-for-the-next-6-months/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/my-kde-e2-80-99s-priorities-for-the-next-6-months/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Summary of last 6 months:</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;More or less 6 months ago I put myself a list of objective to accomplish in KDE, so far these are the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth: We've been working hard in the last release of BlueDevil (1.1), now we can say that more or less KDE has a good Bluetooth support :)!&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webcam: Kamoso 2.0 has been released, and with it rock solid support to do the basics such Take a picture, or Record a video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;﻿XRandR: The job has been started, I've in a private repository a fork of xrandrtray libraries, and the &quot;configuration&quot; has been decoupled from the actual XRandR code. More important I have a plan for it now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibSolid Async: Nothing on this area, -10 for me :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Ottens former maintainer and overlord of Solid is transferring to me the responsibility, challenge accepted!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zeroconf and Friends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samba has been fixed by rbelem (Rodrigo Belem), there is no place for me there :p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NFS support has been removed (by rbelem too), it has no place between modern user-land protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UPnP: The work on UPnP is about to be merged, I haven't touch a line though I've read a lot about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avahi: KDE Already has a good support for Avahi, though we've to improve how we present it to the user. No plans here and I won't be working on it anytime soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost nothing... Though I'm still willing to work on it starting by analyzing the current situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I'm quite proud of myself though I haven't accomplish everything I wanted since right now my priority is my &quot;real life&quot; job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, next post is going to be about what I'm going to do for the next 6 months... stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/summary-of-last-6-months/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/summary-of-last-6-months/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Bits of Platform11</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we will be all leaving towards our respective homes and platform11 will be formally done, though the work is far to be finished. In this blogspot I'm not going to talk about that though :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to talk about how important these events are beyond the technical expects and what I'm going to say applies to my experience in this sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can &quot;Put faces&quot; to people, you're no longer talking to &quot;dfaure&quot; or &quot;apachelloger&quot; or... you're talking to a person, you know how they're and more or less how they think, and that makes the communication much more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brotherhood is enhanced, after don't let anyone sleep because there are 3 people in a &quot;snoring championship&quot; you get some confidence with the group :p this improve the way we work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge is transfered: Do you know the reason why KToolInvocation is using KLaunch to execute apps and at the same time KLaunch is using kdeinit ? I didn't know before a dinosaur told me the reason :p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unify positions: During this sprint I've seen people saying NO! to something end up by saying yes, the amount of things that can be discussed in person are way bigger than via email or irc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast integration feel for newcomers: People that have been contributing into KDE for month's or even years started the sprint saying: &lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt; have to... When &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;... and end up saying: &lt;strong&gt;We&lt;/strong&gt; have to... When &lt;strong&gt;we&lt;/strong&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to sump up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprints are NOT only about core, are also about People and because of that, they're extremely important for the health of KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks you all that make possible to organize such events, and particularly thanks for &lt;a title=&quot;Join The Game&quot; href=&quot;http://jointhegame.kde.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joining the game&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bits-of-platform11/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bits-of-platform11/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I can't find myself :/ though I can be anybody else</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the Randa sprint (platform11, multimedia, kdevelop, nepomuk) we were given a badge so other people can see who we are and so on. One day (maybe two) after that, somebody started to exchange them until the point that I've been around 30different persons in 2 days xD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I started to look for myself again since I like to keep this things but seems that nobody has it :/ maybe somebody throw me to the trash? xD is impressive how small things like this can become incredibly funny when you're in this kind of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is clearly not me :p&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Hugo &quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/hugo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/i-cant-find-myself-though-i-can-be-anybody-else/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/i-cant-find-myself-though-i-can-be-anybody-else/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kamoso 2.0 Velázquez released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We're proud to announce the final version of Kamoso Velázquez, the KDE picture/video retriever !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release we've focused all the effort on getting the most stable release possible, and so far we think that we've reached that goal until it's matching our expectatives. This version is more important than what it seems, with this release we're making a new technology switch towards QtGstreamer, a technology that we hope will allow us to offer a stable, consistent and scalable application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the main features of Kamoso 2.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take pictures from your webcam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record videos from your webcam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Per device video settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for multiple cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the pictures  directly to facebook (need kipi-plugins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the videos to youtube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source tarball can be downloaded from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/kamoso/2.0/src/kamoso-2.0-final.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/kamoso/2.0.2/src/kamoso-2.0.2.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/kamoso/2.0.2/src/kamoso-2.0.2.tar.bz2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;md5: ﻿﻿c2125e3cbe10ddc397ec4308891a9f4c&lt;br /&gt;
sha1: 3eb081446cb1a4ced6602f01cc3209fb188d0b96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kamoso-2-0-velazquez-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kamoso-2-0-velazquez-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.1, Three different ways of sending files.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about &quot;File Sending&quot; in BlueDevil 1.1, and area that has been highly improved in this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had mainly three complains about the 1.0 version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wizard was too complicated with too many pages &lt;a title=&quot;Bug filled on bugs.kde.org&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=254508&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No way of sending files via Terminal or from other Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No way of sending files from Konqueror/Dolphin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to remark one thing before continuing, the first point of the list was reported in a proper way in the right place, by adding a bug in http://bugs.kde.org , and the process until we get the right solution was &quot;beautiful&quot;, getting feedback from a different user of who reported the bug int he first place. So &lt;strong&gt;please&lt;/strong&gt;! instead of comment blogs, if you want to be sure that you feature is not going to get lost, report it on the bko, we will be glad to help you in any way we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let's start by showing the old wizard process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; caption=&quot;BlueDevil old send files&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/steps_old.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;BlueDevil old send files&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/steps_old_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;BlueDevil old send files&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that have been reduced to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; caption=&quot;New wizard single step&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/steps_new.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;New wizard single step&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/steps_new.png&quot; alt=&quot;New wizard single step&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite an improvement, eh? idea inspired by &lt;em&gt;Martin Koller at &lt;a title=&quot;Bug filled on bugs.kde.org&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=254508&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we had the terminal/application problem, solved by adding 2 new options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; caption=&quot;New terminal options&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/terminal.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;  &quot; title=&quot;New terminal options&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;New terminal options&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, we get to one of the most requested features, sending files from konqueror and dolphin !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; caption=&quot;Dolphin sending bluetooth files&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/dolphin_bluetooth.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; &quot; title=&quot;Dolphin sending bluetooth files&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/dolphin_bluetooth.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dolphin sending bluetooth files&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; caption=&quot;Konqui sending files!&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/konqui_bluetooth.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; &quot; title=&quot;Konqui sending files!&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/konqui_bluetooth.png&quot; alt=&quot;Konqui sending files!&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;381&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you like the changes and as always the mandatory video:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_sendfile.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_sendfile.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See you in the next post: BlueDevil 1.1, The new Pairing Wizard&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-three-different-ways-of-sending-files/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-three-different-ways-of-sending-files/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.1, the new SystemTray</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With the 1.1 BlueDevil version, the system tray has been improved adding new features as well of revising the usability, this is the new aspect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;302&quot; caption=&quot;BlueDevil 1.1 system tray&quot;]&lt;img title=&quot;BlueDEvil 1.1 system tray&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_systemtray.png&quot; alt=&quot;BlueDevil 1.1 system tray&quot; width=&quot;302&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the old 1.0 system tray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; caption=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0 system tray&quot;]&lt;img title=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0 system tray&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_old_systemtray.png&quot; alt=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0 system tray&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few changes can be notice here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most common actions have been placed at the top and at the bottom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The configuration action have been merged to just &quot;Configure Bluetooth&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of known devices is homogenous with no separator between types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active/Disable discoverable mode has been added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &quot;Turn off&quot; for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small overlay icon indicating that at least there is one device connected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooltip (not visible at the screenshot) indicating if there is any activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're now quite happy with our most important interface, its usage is fast and it is feature complete, because of that no new changes are expected, though we may work on a plasmoid to replace it, but that is at least for +2 versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, here it is the mandatory video:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_systray.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bluedevil_systray.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next review: Three different ways of sending files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-the-new-systemtray/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-1-the-new-systemtray/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.4 released</title>
				<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth patch version or our KDE Bluetooth Stack, this time containing an important fix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unregister the agent correctly (important)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't launch the wizard if the input device doesn't require pairing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil tarball:&lt;br /&gt;
md5sum: 016e8b048bd834548a436fb0440667a9&lt;br /&gt;
download: &lt;a title=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0.4 tarball&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;br /&gt;
This version, as the one before (1.0.3) depends on libbluedevil 1.8.1, so be sure to ship them both!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tag and tarball for 1.1 are done, I will try to publish a graphic/video changelog shortly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-4-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-4-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New BlueDevil releases are coming</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In a few days we will be released the fourth &quot;patch version&quot; of our KDE Bluetooth stack together with the second &quot;featured version&quot; 1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that point, we will be changing our release policy to a &quot;Release Soon Release Often&quot;, which is the natural next step since BlueDevil reaching maturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next days, I will try to make a post each day explaining the new features and changes in BlueDevil 1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers and Happy Hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/new-bluedevil-releases-are-comming/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/new-bluedevil-releases-are-comming/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Respect me and my freedom</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In my way to work I have been thinking in something that happened the other day, I was showing/explaining to a coworker some mobile applications made with web technologies and discussing about Android/MeeGo/&lt;del&gt;iPhone&lt;/del&gt; development. After a few minutes of good conversation the next chat happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;coworker: Maybe we can even create a Windows Phone application&lt;br /&gt;
me: I'm not going to install nor use Windows  and even less I'm going to write an application for Windows Phone.&lt;br /&gt;
coworker: C'mon  you should not be that radical&lt;br /&gt;
me: Excuses for being a radical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after thinking about this chat with a cold mind, I started to wonder the little respect that people have for others with different values, for example I know people that thinks that being a Vegetarian is stupid and foolish, or that everybody who have a religion is dumb. This issue is no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't do anything for those with closed minds, for those who currently don't respect anything beyond their values and beliefs but I can tell something to everybody else:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you won't force a vegetarian to eat meat, if you won't force a Muslim to eat pork, if you won't force others to do what you do, please don't force me to use private software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I (L) Freedom&lt;br /&gt;
I (L) My Computer Freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/respect-me-and-my-freedom/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/respect-me-and-my-freedom/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.3 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;While working on BlueDevil 1.1 we've found time to release the third &quot;patch release&quot; of our KDE Bluetooth Stack, so here is the changelog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed requestPin helper by flushing cout buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed requestConfirmation by passing the correct arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BUG: 267302 (crash reproducible for example with an iPhone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved wizard device name detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &quot;Send files&quot; in some system by being sure that the defaultAdapter is NOT discovering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this version we're releasing also libbluedevil 1.8.1, with the following changelog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workarounded bluez consistency for default adapter (this will fix some adapter detection errors).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new signal to fix device scanning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil tarball:&lt;br /&gt;
md5sum: a2d4aa126f86dbc1f429a3aa9e95671d&lt;br /&gt;
download: &lt;a title=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0.3 tarball&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.3/src/bluedevil-1.0.3.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibBluedevil tag:&lt;br /&gt;
git clone git://anongit.kde.org/libbluedevil; cd libbluedevil; git checkout v1.8.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;br /&gt;
The new version of libbluedevil is a dependency of the 1.0.3, so be sure to install them both! without the new library the wizard's won't work!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is it for now, stay tunned because we'll start to publish information about 1.1 soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-3-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-3-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.2 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The second minor version of BlueDevil (KDE's Bluetooth support) has been released and it is the most important release since 1.0 because it adds support for some basic bluetooth feature we have been missing since 1.0, regarding Device Pairing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The full changelog is&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Bluetooth 2.1 (SSP pairing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not pair devices that don’t need it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better automatic mode (Updated PIN database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Randomized the default PIN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random PIN of 6 characters, shrink if needed (depending on device)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the wizard flow for a lot of devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not show actions in systray when offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handle possible obex-data-server crashes (This is the cause for a looooooot of troubles receiving files.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed big file operations in kio_obexftp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The i18n should be fixed once for all (stable branch created)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tarbal can be downloaded &lt;a title=&quot;BlueDevil download&quot; href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=stable/bluedevil/1.0.2/src/bluedevil-1.0.2.tar.bz2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
MD5: c0c814146098b865144957bc8b3bd7e7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now almost all distributions have packages, so if your distribution doesn't poke them because this release is very important stability-wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-2-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-2-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What is Kamoso</title>
				<description>&lt;div&gt;A lot of people has been asking me (or complaining)  what is Kamoso and what we intend to do with it, so I've decided to use a  blog post to explain it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short Description:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Kamoso is an application for taking Pictures and Videos using any webcam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kamoso is an application between two worlds, &quot;Multimedia&quot; and &quot;Toys&quot;.  While its main propose may be seen as just &quot;Take Pictures&quot; and &quot;Take  Videos&quot;, our plan goes beyond that: we are planning to add a bunch of  effects that will allow to the user to play with the webcam, we want it  to be fun, in the end. All of these is followed by a tightly integration  with the Web 2.0, by adding export features to the most common Web 2.0  services, such YouTube, Facebook, twitpic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current 2.0 (aka Velázquez):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Kamoso rock solid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We moved to QtGStreamer (part of the last point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve interface usability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.0 (Future):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;Effects: investigate what GStreamer offers and try to get the best out of it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;Simplify Web 2.0 integration: make it easier to add support for new services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;Interface candy: make the interface more appealing to the eye, properly integrate the effects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screenshoots:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; caption=&quot;Kamoso 1&quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;  &quot; title=&quot;Kamoso 1&quot; src=&quot;http://afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/kamoso1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;570&quot; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Kamoso 2&quot; src=&quot;http://afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/kamoso2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;571&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/kamoso-2.ogv&quot;&gt;Small review of Kamoso 2.0&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/kamoso2.ogv&quot;&gt;Pre 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help needed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semaphore designs (What happens from when you click at the shot button, and when the picture is actually taken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mockups, ideas, whatever!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/what-is-kamoso/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/what-is-kamoso/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First version of Kamoso 2.0 (Velázquez) released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After few months of work, we're glad to announce the availability of Kamoso 2.0-alpha2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite of being an alpha version, it has demostrated to perform quite stable in all the test we did during the alpha1 (this was a private release), in fact judging by the feedback we got&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this version is way more stable than 1.0.5, so give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changelog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso now uses QtGstreamer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements in the interface (by Andrew Lake)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New semaphore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &amp;quot;action&amp;quot; non hidden features by adding a new button to &amp;quot;share&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &amp;quot;share&amp;quot; button to improve feature discoverability.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better Nepomuk integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more audio/video synchronitation problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Errata:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crash when switching from &amp;quot;Record Video&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Photo&amp;quot; mode (some times)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test needed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need test in different environments with different webcams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take picture and then upload it to Facebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record a video, and then upload it to Youtube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this version we're confident of the quality and future that Kamoso can achieve, because of that when 2.0-final is released, we will move Kamoso to kdereview, and if accepted to extragear/multimedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source Tarball can be downloaded at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://download.kde.org/download.php?url=unstable/kamoso/2.0-alpha2/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/kamoso-2.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/kamoso-2.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blogilo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/first-version-of-kamoso-2-0-velazquez-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/first-version-of-kamoso-2-0-velazquez-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil (stable) testing needed</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we released 1.0, we've been working hard to stabilize BlueDevil as much as possible and after fixing a bunch of bugs in kio_obexftp, now it's turn for the wizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the changelog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Bluetooth 2.1 (SSP pairing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not pair devices that don't need it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better automatic mode (Updated PIN database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Randomized the default PIN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random PIN of 6 characters, shrink if needed (depending on device)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the flow for lot of devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are plenty changes for a minor release and that's why we need some testing before release BlueDevil 1.0.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is already packaged in OpenSuse KDE:Unstable:Playground and to build it from the source you have to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;git clone git://git.kde.org/bluedevil&lt;br /&gt;
cd bluedevil&lt;br /&gt;
git checkout stable&lt;br /&gt;
cmake ./ -DCMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX=/usr (well this depends on your installation)&lt;br /&gt;
make -j3 install (you will probably need root for this).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have arrived here, you've got extra credits:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/bluedevil-wizard.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/bluedevil-wizard.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-stable-testing-needed/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-stable-testing-needed/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Improving KDE Applications Help menu &quot;Actions Lookup&quot;</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I have been working on a small &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_concept&quot;&gt;Proof of Concept&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;which intents to demostrate that improve the Help menu by adding an &quot;Actions Lookup&quot; is possible.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;At the moment this is not a planned feature, so is not going to be in KDE Platform 4.6 or even not in 4.7. If the overall feedback I get during the next days is positive I will start a brainstorming (in kde-usability I guess?) to design the feature and try to implement it for 4.7.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/actionSearch.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/actionSearch.ogv&quot;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Some ideas I have in my mind:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to use it as we use KRunner (shortcut + write text + enter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something to show where the action is (so the user can learn the app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search within the Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online search?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;What do you think? would be useful have something like that in our platform?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Cyap!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/improving-kde-applications-help-menu-actions-lookup/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/improving-kde-applications-help-menu-actions-lookup/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0.1 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The first minor version of BlueDevil has been released.
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The changelog is:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the overall stability of kio_obexftp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &quot;Empty device name&quot; bug by making the wizards scan until the name is fetched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The arbal can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/bluedevil-1.0.1.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with md5sum:&amp;nbsp;4558dd739a58978b93d513a45d6e6b35&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;A new minor release can be expected in a few days, fixing some possible bugs in the Agent.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-1-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-1-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Nepomuk is not fast, is instant!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody that has been a KDE user for the last 2 years knows Nepomuk and its bad reputation, maybe it was desired in the past, but no more. This morning I decided to get my Nepomuk up and running again, and I have to say that it is impresive! just take a look at &lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/instantNepomuk.ogv&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/instantNepomuk.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The only thing I had to do is modify a kernel configuration, but I had to do it because my distributionb (ArchLinux) didn't for me, others like Ubuntu or OpenSuse have the correct value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Execute:&lt;br /&gt;
sysctl fs.inotify.max_user_watches&lt;br /&gt;
fs.inotify.max_user_watches = 524288&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get a value such 8000 then you have to change it, to do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;echo &quot;fs.inotify.max_user_watches = 524288&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/sysctl.conf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I'm missing now is a good plasmoid (Crystal to the rescue?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: I'm using trunk (4.6), but afaik Nepomuk should be as fast as in 4.5&lt;br /&gt;
Dolphin searchbar is a feature found in 4.6 (to be released in 2 months)&lt;br /&gt;
If you update the parameter using sysctl command remember to restart nepomuk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/nepomuk-is-not-fast-is-instant/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/nepomuk-is-not-fast-is-instant/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meego Conference, day 1</title>
				<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As you may guess, I'm in Ireland like a lot of other hackers attending the MeeGo conference. I've been here since Saturday and so far I love the city and the people in here, lovely place.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Today (Monday 15) has been the first day of the conference and it has been great, good organization and a good general mood provoked by a mix of &quot;enthusiasm and desire change things&quot;. Maybe the worst part of the day has been discovering how little bit people know about us (KDE), many people know more or less what we are (A Desktop), but nothing solid, even some of them got surprised when I told them that the entire KDE SC is made by using Qt, definitely we've room for improvement in spreading our community and our software.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As a final note, today I've got a N900 from Nokia (Thanks!), can't wait to hack on it and try to run Kamoso in there, would be awesome, wouldn't it?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Time to sleep, cyap!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/meego-conference-day-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/meego-conference-day-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kamoso is alive!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After months of being almost a dead-zombie project now the Kamoso development has been resumed, we can say that it is in better shape than ever!&amp;nbsp;Motivated by the QtGstreamer project, Aleix and I decided to port Kamoso to it and see how it goes (it has been the perfect excuse to revive the project). So far we didn't regret the change. Besides the technology switch (we we're kind of ok with libvlc), the change has given to us new forces to work on the project, let's see what we've got so far:
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Current features:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload pictures to facebook (kipi plugins export interface)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload videos to youtube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burst mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smoother thumbnails view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fancy overlay icons to indicate what files are being uploaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Work in progress:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some logic to decide what microphone to use (depending on platform).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook video support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose webcam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitpic support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The application is quite stable right now, so we're open for feedback, to compile it you have to:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;1-Have gstreamer installed (base and good plugins are needed)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;2-Have QtGstreamer (&lt;a href=&quot;http://gitorious.org/qtgstreamer&quot;&gt;http://gitorious.org/qtgstreamer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;3-Get Kamoso sources from &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.kde.org/projects/playground/multimedia/kamoso&quot;&gt;git.kde.org:kamoso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Well make a release shortly, for the waiting here comes a Kamoso2 &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/kamoso2.ogv&quot;&gt;funny video&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The video's recorded in the screencast are uploaded &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9wWuavZeJ7Y&quot;&gt;Ereslibre Sexy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtjq70vKhUM&quot;&gt;Ereslibre Monkey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/kamoso2.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Cya and Happy Hacking!&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kamoso-is-alive/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kamoso-is-alive/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My KDE's way (for the next 6 months)</title>
				<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Today, is the last day of my holidays, I could say that it is pity, but it is not, I'm addicted to my work :$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;During this relax vacations, I've dedicated a part of the time into analize the current situation of KDE, and with that try to find my spot between all the work that needs to be done. Probably during the next days I will publish some blog entries with the cloncusions got, but this entry is about what I'm going to do in KDE in the follow 6 months. I think that having an agenda and try to achieve it is very important to do not get distracted in the way. KDE is a big community with a lot of work to be done, is important to have clear where you want to help, and try&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;to find the balance between &quot;What have to be done&quot; and &quot;What you want to do&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;One of the best and most impresive facets of KDE, is our implication in a lot of fields, from office applications, to &quot;The cloud&quot;, passing trhough PIM. With all these options, is not trivial to decide where to collaborate, again find the balance between &quot;Where I'm needed&quot; and &quot;Where I want to be&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Taking into account all of that, this is my conclusion:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;One of the most frustrating things when you install KDE in a PC, is not been able to use some kind of hardware, for example: Webcams, Bluetooth,  Printers... This is somethign weird since all mentioned before have an excelent support in GNU/Linux. A lot of this things are more or less supported (printers for example), but they don't have the elegance we are looking for. Other types of hardware like the finger readers are not supported at all althought there are some work done there. This is my TODO list:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue the BlueDevil development (Bluetooth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revive Kamoso (Webcam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XRandR support (Screen management).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibSolid asynchronous API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zeroconf and friends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;A few weeks ago, I was using empathy when I noticed somebody called &quot;Alfredo Rollan&quot; in my contact list. I started to wonder who was that guy, and what was he doing in my contact list... After a while I remembered Bonjour, so I ran trhough everybody using osx to see if any of them was the so called &quot;Alfredo&quot;, and indeed I found him. That event started my curiosity about Bonjour, Avahi and  Zeroconf. I started to perform the typical searchs: &quot;Avahi KDE&quot; &quot;Zeroconf KDE&quot;... Then I discover our kio network:// and that kopete actually supports Bonjour (but you've to create the account yourself). After seeing the potential of this, I think that is very important for us beeing able to support these technologies. Image for example being at akademy and just after you connect your computer to the network you start to see a lot of people in your contact list, everybody wil be able to share the akademy photos just by clicking in one button, and you will be able to reach them just by using your file browser, all of this without configuring anything. I don't have clear what I want to do in this topic, so before do anything I will:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate Avahi, and what KDE supports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate UPnP, and what KDE supports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate Samba, and what KDE supports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate NFS, and what KDE supports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small things here and there:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Something that is annoying me from the current status of KDE software is that some things are &quot;half working&quot; or at least they are for me, and some other things are lacking the &quot;Elegance&quot; we want to achieve. List of things I want to do:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate CUPS and all the &quot;printing&quot; thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate PulseAudio and KDE Sound system (kmix, phonon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As some of you may know, where I work we have the fridays free to work on what we want, the idea is to give something back to the community. After much thinking, I belive that the best I can do in that 8hours is improve the documentation in KDE. This is not a final TODO:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand how doxygen work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at how KDE uses doxygen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at how Qt and other projects does it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the current techbase layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trace a plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;A lot of things to do, and only 6 months ahead, beter stop talking and start to do some fresh autumn hacking :)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Happy hacking!&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/my-kdes-way-for-the-next-6-months/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/my-kdes-way-for-the-next-6-months/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>One step closer towards a KDE hal-free</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the objectives that the solid team is currently working on, is the deprecation/removing of HAL as KDE dependency. We hope to accomplish it for KDE 4.6, but of course at the moment it is just that, a wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow the complete remove is now a step closer, thanks to Dario Freddi and Lukas Tinkl I just committed the &amp;quot;PowerDevil 2 UPower&amp;quot; backend. Right now, it is build by default but is not used if the hal backend is compiled too, so in case you want to test it you have to edit powerdevilupowerbackend.desktop and set InitialPreference = 20 (lower than the hal one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small entry for a small thing, but small things matter don't they?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/one-step-closer-towards-a-kde-hal-free/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/one-step-closer-towards-a-kde-hal-free/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Solid Sprint 2010, from my Point Of View</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Almost 1 week has passed since Solid Sprint took place, and I'm already waiting for the next event, where I can hack side by side with KDE hackers from all the world again (Maybe in the Meego conference?). It was a short sprint but intense, productive and funny, on where we discussed and worked on some different topics. Let's began from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organisation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organisation of a small Sprint doesn't require a huge amount of time (at least didn't this one) basically the tasks to do are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure that you can attend to the sprinters and having a good place for the event (&lt;a title=&quot;War Room&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/5042758200_27c13020ea_z.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;office&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose the idea and the place to some KDE group (&lt;a title=&quot;Mailing list&quot; href=&quot;http://mail.kde.org/pipermail/kde-hardware-devel/2010-August/000962.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mailist&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide a date doing a &lt;a title=&quot;Doodle service&quot; href=&quot;http://www.doodle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;poll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare a budget for the e.V board (&lt;a title=&quot;Attendees list&quot; href=&quot;http://community.kde.org/Solid/Sprint2010#Attendees_List&quot;&gt;attendees list&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send the budget to the board, together with the event explanation and wait.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally book the rooms, and enjoy the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, &lt;a title=&quot;UFOCoders site&quot; href=&quot;www.ufocoders.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UFOCoders&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&quot;Interdominio's site&quot; href=&quot;www.interdominios.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interdominios&lt;/a&gt; sponsored catering for all the weekend (food and drinks), and Pizza for the Sunday lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After met everybody in the room where the event took place, we went to lunch. After it we began to organize the Sprint, or better said Kevin Ottens start to explain to the rest of the team all the things that were filling the whiteboard (an entire glass wall), in it we could differ between &quot;Discussing goals&quot; and &quot;Coding goals&quot;, these last were managed by using a Kanban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important point we discussed (imho) is the &quot;Solid as a Team&quot; one. That was something that everybody had in his mind, but it was not official. Now it is, so welcome the new Solid, reborn as a community inside KDE, containing a lot of projects like (in no particular order): libsolid, powerdevil, networkmanagement, bluedevil... So, if you have a project which is related to KDE+Hardware, don't hesitate to contact us via kde-hardware-devel mailist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having discussed all the topics, we started to hack. That night (Friday) we established the first interaction between NetworkManagement and BlueDevil, it not was event using an interface or any BD/NM code, but it demonstrated to us how hard/easy it was, and that it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few hours of Hacking, Sebas, Dario, and I went to take some beers (Voll daaamn :D), near de hotel, and discuss about random things. I love these discussions! exchange opinions and ideas about our ecosystem is, a part of entertaining and funny, one learnt a lot of things by listening to other point of views, and make your global vision better. The bad thing (if I can say something) is that I slept 4h that night :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Middle&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Saturday was the &quot;Super Hacking Day&quot;, we where in front of the computer for around 18 hours only stopping for dinner. Each person on the sprint had lunch at a different time which shows how deep where were in our personal thought's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I decided to do that Saturday was finish my part of Bluetooth+NetworkManagement. If started to implement some plugins for BlueDevil, when doing it I noticed some interesting stuff from BlueZ, and discover how Network interface work. So, I explained to Will what I discovered and the issues I found, and he started to research how GNOME applet/wizard handle it. I don't remember when, but we ended up with a solution (Will did), so we hope that sooner than later we'll have Bluetooth+NetworkManagement interaction done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task I assigned to myself was a technical one (not directly user-related), add asynchronous API to libsolid. After discussin with Kevin his design, I used the next hours to learn how libsolid works, and to connect the current code with the Kevin explanation about the new design. Once I did that, I started to write some tests that will help me to design a good API and at the same time that this new API would be &quot;unit tested&quot; (basicaly I sued Test Driven Development). With the tsdgeos help, we got a PoC working, that helped us to decided which way we should take (use an internal QList instead of inherit it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An finally, I started to do some fine tune into BlueDevil Wizard, to get the pairing process more stable and perfect with a major number of devices (devices without PIN mainly). I tested the new code with: Apple* stuff I grabbed from the office, Nokia headset, HTC Magic and Wiimote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the hacking session at 6am, and decided to come back at 10am, so basically I decided to do not sleep (wise decision).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the ends are sad, even if it is a good end. In the sprint cases, it is sad because the people leave in dribs and drabs, however we managed to get a profitable time to put a good end to the Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the objectives of this sprint was exchange projects or topics, so instead of continue hacking on BlueDevil, I decided to take another project task, in this case PowerDevil UPower Backend. So, as Dario was sitting just left to me, I asked him to explain me how to create a PowerDevil2 backend, and after he explained to me, I started to copy some code from the Hal backend and make it compile. After it we just ordered some pizza's (Sponsored too, as the tradition says) and well, we bought too much :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch I continued with my research, this time focused on UPower, basically I compared UPower vs Hal features (the ones we are using) and noticed some things that have to be done by using another piece of software, like xrandr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we end up Sebas, Ereslibre, and I. In one of the trips to the fridge we noticed something... there were 6 Volldamn left to drink! We decided to add a sticky note (Green + Red which meant Community and Urgency), and add it to &quot;In Progress&quot; column. After a hard work and a lot of chatting, we moved the task to the &quot;Done&quot; column :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While packing and cleaning everything, we end up at 02:00 AM talking about random stuff again, sharing ideas about KDE future, Sebas showing to us Lionmail and Crystal etc...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To end the post, I'd like to thank for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-KDE e.V for sponsoring the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Community: people and companies, who donate money to e.V, so they can sponsor the sprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a title=&quot;Interdominio's site&quot; href=&quot;www.interdominios.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interdominios&lt;/a&gt; for helping us with the organisation (Specially to Benito, who handled all the catering and Hotel booking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Solid team to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty much all, I hope this post help you (reader) to realize how important these sprints are for us, and by extension how important the donations are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Join the game link&quot; href=&quot;http://jointhegame.kde.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join the game!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/vizzzion/5048391846/sizes/l/in/set-72157624950127005/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Solid Team&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/5048391846_d4da10eb69_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solid Team&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-2010-from-my-point-of-view/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-2010-from-my-point-of-view/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Solid Sprint day 1, go!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;So, almost everybody is here finally (Albert will come tomorrow Saturday), and it has been a very profitable day. We have finished the &quot;boring&quot; stuff like discussing who we are (We're the Solid team now! be aware of that :p), discussing how we can improve the upstream communication (driver developers, blueZ, u*disk/power etc) and stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After it, we've done some hacking (not a lot in my case), but we managed to get Bluetooth-DUN and Bluetooth-NAP working, and we did it in like 5minutes... is what Sprints are about, right? :) put Lamarque (modemmanager) and bluedevil developers together and you will get Bluetooth+Networking working :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, going to sleep since the hacking will be resumed in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todo wall-list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Solid Sprint-hacker-wall&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/hacker-wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-day-1-go/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-day-1-go/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Solid Sprint day 0</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly everything is ready for the Solid Sprint that is going to take place in Madrid, we got 1Gb connection, 50&amp;quot; flat screen, food, drinks, beer, coffee and of course a lot of code &amp;quot;hungry&amp;quot; :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebas is already here to attend some KDE e.V stuff together with ereslibre (vice-president of KDE-España), we have had a good dinner (typical spanish bar) and now is time to sleep so tomorrow we can be with our hacker skills at 100%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, see you tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I wrote this post yesterday (Thursday).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-day-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/solid-sprint-day-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0rc4 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After a lot of work, and a lot of testing done by a lot of people the RC4 is here and we hope it will be the last one before the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a crash in the file receiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a crash in the KDED&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned audio UUID's (less false positives in the wizard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Audio Sink support in the systray application (Patch by Peter Korf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some i18n work (not perfect tough)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of work in kio_obexftp, it should be stable now, test it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some times the systray application is not updated correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kio_obexftp is stable, but some times has weird behaviours (testers needed!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kio_obexftp &amp;quot;rename&amp;quot; action is not working in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use the RC4 tag, use RC4-1 instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tarball can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil-v1.0rc4-1.tgz&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with md5: c967bce0edd20c2937db5071c7b735df&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And git tag: git clone git://gitorious.org/bluedevil/bluedevil.git; cd bluedevil; git checkout v1.0-rc4-1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help needed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we hope that this will be the last Release Candidate, we need a lot of test to get the final version rock solid, so please test test and test!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a small video of what we can do with the kio's inside BlueDevil:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/obexftp.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/obexftp.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc4-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc4-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Delays delays delays :(</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, BlueDevil RC4 is not out (yet), and there is a reason for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're mainly 2 developers working on it, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ereslibre.es/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;ereslibre&lt;/a&gt; and myself. Ereslibre is studying hard because he has like 5 exams in 2 weeks, and I'm looking for a new place to live downtown (still in Madrid), so those things are stealing our KDE hacking time :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don't worry, BlueDevil development is not paralyzed, luckily our company (ufocoders) is allowing us to work on BlueDevil all Fridays, and this is why we're moving the releases to that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current TODO list until 1.0 final is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few reported crashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better audio plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation for distributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make kio_obexftp stable (this may involve a rewrite, or maybe wait until kde 4.5.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setup bluedevil.kde.org.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I'm not going to write a date, since we can't be sure to accomplish it, but we want to release the RC4 in 2 weeks more or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyap and sorry for the inconveniences!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/delays-delays-delays/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/delays-delays-delays/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0rc3 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This release has been delayed 1 week (as you can see) because we didn't had anything to release (no commits, no fixes), sorry for that! vacations are in the middle :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge improvement on systray application stability, should not crash anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a crash in the Wizard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some small bugs in the KCM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the error list in: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?quicksearch=bluedevil&quot;&gt;KDE Bugtrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this release is not ready to work on i18n, it is expected in RC4 (finally!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tarball can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil-v1.0rc3.tgz&quot; title=&quot;BlueDevil 1.0rc3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with md5: 918d123aa7239fcc42a87fc3e3b418bd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And git tag: git clone git://gitorious.org/bluedevil/bluedevil.git; cd bluedevil; git checkout v1.0-rc3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, as always test BlueDevil as much as possible so we can fix the majority of the bugs before the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next release: 2010/08/25 (next week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc3-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc3-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0rc2 released</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As promised, we have released a new RC of BlueDevil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed BlueZ documentation to avoid licence problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build system fixes by George Kiagiadakis and Kishore Jonnalagadda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the stability of the kio_obexftp (the / bugs has been fixed too).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a crash in the KCM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed crash in the &amp;quot;reception of files&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the error list in: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?quicksearch=bluedevil&quot; title=&quot;KDE Bugtrack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KDE Bugtrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this release is not ready to work on i18n, it is expected in RC3 or 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tarbal can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil-v1.0rc2.tgz&quot; title=&quot;BlueDevil download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with md5: 9af87be2eeffe3b203a06232ef55bfb9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And git tag: git clone git://gitorious.org/bluedevil/bluedevil.git; git checkout v1.0-rc2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, test BlueDevil as much as possible so we can fix the majority of the bugs before the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next release: 2010/08/11 (next week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc2-released/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0rc2-released/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Taking a break</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if we don't want to, our brains need to rest, they need to disconnect from everything and break with the routine of every day, and this is for what the holidays are for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow my actual vacations start, I will be in Paris (again :p) having some family time for a week. I will be online on irc/jabber and I will try read my email everyday but do not expect a quick answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the airports/planes I will probably give some love to Kamoso, with a bit of luck we can do a release some time soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ps: My next entries will be boring things about my vacations, so be ready for that :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/taking-a-break/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/taking-a-break/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil, the new KDE bluetooth stack is here</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We're proud to announce the first release of BlueDevil, the new bluetooth stack for KDE SC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlueDevil is a set of components, which integrates bluetooth within the KDE SC, for example adding a system preference module (KCM), or allowing to browse the files in a cell phone from you favorite file browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of already implemented components is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System preference module (KCM) to configure all the options regarding Bluetooth (also fully activate/deactivate it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with the KDE input/output system (KIO), which allows to discover and explore all bluetooth devices around from your favorite file browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wizard to pair your devices, and connect directly to the compatible services, such input (mouse, keybaord, Wiimote) and audio (headsets, phones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systray application integrated with the last KDE SC 4.5, from where all BlueDevil actions can be done (disconnect devices, send files, configure...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daemon to listen incoming petitions, for example to receive files, or to introduce a requested PIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependencies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bluez (to get it working)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;obex-data-server (for receiving files, and KIO's)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;obexd-client (for sending files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE SC 4.4 or greater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PulseAudio, or a proper configured Alsa (with the bluetooth hook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using kio_obexftp in dolphin on a KDE SC 4.4, some times it won't load the content because more than one kio is launched at the same time and it is not supported by the backend (Tip: Disable the previews or use konqueror)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In KDE 4.5 SC, some times when a device is removed, the systray is not correctly updated (Seems to be a bug in QDBusMenu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When trying to open a file from a bluetooth device, the progress gets stucked at 99%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release should be stable enough to be used by everybody, but we're looking specially for advanced users with &quot;compiling skills&quot; so we can get quick feedback and fix as many bugs as possible. if you are Interested send an email to Àlex (at) ufocoders dot com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internationalization:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently BlueDevil is not ready to be translated (the strings are not final), and we're looking for native English speakers who can help us with the strings, interested people send an email to Àlex {at) ufocoders.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special thanks to (in no particular order):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;BlueZ site&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bluez.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BlueZ&lt;/a&gt; developers and community for their help during the development (and patience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;David Faure Page&quot; href=&quot;http://www.davidfaure.fr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Faure&lt;/a&gt; for his help during the development and infinite patience talking about KIO's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To &lt;a title=&quot;UFO coders page&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ufocoders.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ufocoders&lt;/a&gt; for sponsor half of the development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obtaining the code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the tag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git clone git://gitorious.org/bluedevil/bluedevil.git; git checkout v1.0-rc1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next release we'll provide the proper tarball.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-the-new-kde-bluetooth-stack-is-here/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-the-new-kde-bluetooth-stack-is-here/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BlueDevil 1.0 Review</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, a little bit of historyFirst, a little bit of history&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It Seems that was yesterday when a year ago in the Gran Canaria Desktop Summit, Victor sent a file to me through Bluetooth and kdebluetooth saved it in a hidden folder, the file is still there &quot;~/.kbluetooth4/Vídeo003.3gp&quot;. That fact is what made me decide to use my spare time working on kdebluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of work in kbluetooth (the kdebluetooth fork I did), it started to work, but that spent hours made me realize that the kbluetooth never would be stable, it is a clear example of spaghetti code. Because of that, we started a new project called BlueDevil. If you're wondering about the name, Edulix came with it while working on the daemon, and it is based on PowerDevil (the name).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few fridays working on it, suddenly a Spanish company sent an email to me, asking for help to develop a Qt library to deal with BlueZ. A couple of emails (and beers) later, they hired us (ufocoders) to write the library, the first big step towards a real BlueDevil was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's known that the best way to fully test a library is by using it a lot, so we started a negotiation to finance the development of BlueDevil, finally we got an agreement, we'll pay it 50% / 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is the boring history, that in my most humble opinion had to be written, now let's start with the review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE Config Module (system preferences)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Bluetooth KCM allows you to configure all the options from a single place, it is divided in 3 pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devices, allows you to switch on/off global KDE Platform Bluetooth integration, and manage your remote devices (add, rename, remove...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File Transfer, allows you to switch on/off the reception of files, and configure where (by default) they will be saved once received.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapters, allows you to configure your adapters, changing the name, the visibility...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/system_settings.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/system_settings.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil Wizard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The wizard allows you to pair with other bluetooth devices, and if they have compatible services connect to them. the highlights are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair with any device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to input service (mouse, keyboard, Wiimote)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to audio service (headset, phones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerfull &quot;auto&quot; PIN Mode, which has a database containing exceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following video, you can see the pair+input connection done with a cellphone, which is used at the final to disconnect itself :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/pairing_input.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/pairing_input.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this one, you can see the connection of a Nokia Headset, and the integration with the system (kmix/phonon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/pairing_audio.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/pairing_audio.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systray:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The systray is executed only if Bluetooth adapters are found, it allows you to do everything you want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure remote devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure adapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure file transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new remove devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to known devices services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/systray.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/systray.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE Input/Output integration (KIO):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The KIO integration allows you to discover and browse your devices from your favorite file browser, the highlights are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show and configure (after clicking on them) the supported services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If supported by the device, browse the files (copy, remove, create dir...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/kio.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/kio.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File reception:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Receive files from other devices is supported and totally integrated with the system (using notifications instead of blocking popups etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/receive_files.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/bluedevil/receive_files.ogv&quot;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we'll be releasing one RC each week until we consider BlueDevil stable enough, so the next release will be Friday 4&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
if you wish to help in the development of BlueDevil, you can contact us in irc.freenode.net #solid and in the kde-hardware-devel mailist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-review/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/bluedevil-1-0-review/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I'm not dead, just working</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been quite busy these days, between Akademy and everything. So thought about writing a small blog entry with the status of the projects where I'm involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KBluetooth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry guys to announce it in that way, but KBluetooth is almost dead. I'll release a new version (0.5) trying to fix all the crashes we're having, and it will be everything from my part. I hope to release that version withing this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamoso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have ported kamoso to vlc1.1 (you can get the code from the proper branch), and it is working quite well. I'd like to release a new (last) stable version which won't crash when the application is closed. After it we'll concentrate our efforts in stabilizing the new code, getting it too work perfect with vlc 1.1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KTuberling&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did almost nothing for 4.5, but I'm planning to do some maintainer work for 4.6, closing bugs (yees! the pepperoni bug too), and I'll try to remove the &amp;quot;blinking&amp;quot;, but I don't know how (yet) :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlueDevil&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, tonight (in 8/10 hours) you'll have news about this one :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetworkManager&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yay! I'm planning to join the group of crazy developers that works on NetworkManager+KDE, the first task I'll try to accomplish is the removal of Solid::Control, for now, I'm reading code code and more code, and I'll do that until I'm able to paint a &amp;quot;virtual map&amp;quot; of what is currently implemented. I don't have a date for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in 8/10 hours with a surprise (a known one :p)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyap!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/im-not-dead-just-working/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/im-not-dead-just-working/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New KDevelop key feature plugin</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We're a lot of developers in KDE, and each of us like to use one or other tool to write code, for example, is known that I love KDevelop, others like vim, emacs, kate, qtcreator, eclipse... But you know what we all do? ask for help :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we've develop a new Plugin for KDevelop which will give us direct access to where all the KDE knowlege is stored&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KDevelop faure&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/kdevelop-faure.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;David Faure Plugin&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/kdevelop-faure.png&quot; alt=&quot;David Faure Plugin&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/new-kdevelop-key-feature-plugin/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/new-kdevelop-key-feature-plugin/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KDE Multimedia Sprint Days 2, 3, 4 and 5</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2: Trip to Zermatt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day was marked by the trip to Zermatt but not by the outward journey but by the return one which I did (as the major part of the people) walking. We went through the forest crossing 2 rivers (well, jumping 2 rivers xD) and of course, talking about software, akademy, politics etc. By the night, a mysterious KHTML crash produced by gcc appeared in my laptop sadly I lost all the hacking time figuring out that gcc was the problem :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3: Kamoso meets j-b (aka vlc man)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember exactly when we introduced Kamoso to j-b, but I do remember that I got stunned because seems that we did it quite well (the usage of libvlc and libvlccore). After a couple of minutes we fixed like 3 kamoso bugs (thanks to j-b). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can say that since them Kamoso is on the road again :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 4 and 5: Kamoso hacking and rediscovering vlc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following days I concentrated all my efforts in 2 topics: port kamoso to vlc 1.1 and stabilization. The port was rather straight, I got the basic features (display and get pictures) working without many problems. Then once I had the base working with vlc 1.1 I started to fix crashes, I was able to smash all of them but one, anyway that one is fixed now (Thanks to the vlc people).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, to fix some bugs I needed the help of the vlc community, j-b pointed me to the guy we had to talk with to fix some problems we had with the audio recording, there was where I realized the healthy community that is behind vlc, which is not only a good project but it is also a good community&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-days-2-3-4-and-5/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-days-2-3-4-and-5/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KDE Multimedia Sprint QuickSand, day 1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For those who know what QuickSand is you may wonder &amp;quot;What is the relationship between QuickSand and Multimedia/Edu?&amp;quot; the answer to that question is quick and short, none :p but it is what I did today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is QuickSand? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QuickSand is an alternative interface for KRunner, it is integrated in KRunner (the code is inside KRunner), and since the major part of KDE users seems to like the default interface almost nobody knows his existence :p, but it actually exists and I can prove it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/QuickSand44.png&quot; title=&quot;QuickSand kde 4.4&quot; alt=&quot;QuickSand kde 4.4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what's up with QuickSand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QuickSand is one of these software (or in this case a part of a program) which were developed in the early days of KDE4 and for some reason the maintainer(s)/authors are &amp;quot;missing&amp;quot; or are not taking care of that code anymore, this may seem sad but Hey! here is where the beautiful of the free software comes to the rescue, any interested developer can contribute and even adopt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I did to QuickSand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically what I did is some &amp;quot;maintarnership&amp;quot;, removing/adding stuff here and there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unhardcoded all the colors (Now they are following the respective KDE/Plasma themes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a button to execute the system activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tunned the interface a little bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some relayouting issues when accessing to the options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &amp;quot;Esc&amp;quot; as a shortcut to close the interface (AAAAH! that was really needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the only known crash (Has been backported to 4.4.4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some other minnors changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/quicksand.png&quot; title=&quot;QuickSand KDE SC 4.5&quot; alt=&quot;QuickSand KDE SC 4.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll write an entire post about QuickSand, I think that it is an interesting concept and I may adopt it in the future (KDE 4.7 at least).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow the hard work on Kamoso will start, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-quicksand-day-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-quicksand-day-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KDE Multimedia Sprint Paris--&gt;Lyon--&gt;Geneve--&gt;Visp--&gt;Rand, day 0</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The train network in the middle of Europe is awesome, but by awesome I mean really awesome :D you can travel from almost all big cities without using the plane, which is by far more comfortable and green than doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reach Randa we had to take 4 trains, that can be painful in some countries (in Spain for example) but in Switzerland the trains have an atomic precision so you don't even need to know the name of the station where you have to &quot;leave&quot;, when you buy the ticket they'll give to you a paper with the schedule, so you only have to be careful with the time :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after that 6/7h of traveling we arrived to Randa, where a bunch of KDE hackers were waiting for us :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town is beautiful, it remembers me to the Heidi Manga (which was inspired by that kind of towns), maybe it is the most beautiful town I ever saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/loussane.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-166&quot; title=&quot;loussane&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/loussane-1024x681.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the travel between Geneve and Visp we stop in Lausanne, the city where my mother was born :p&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-paris-lyon-geneve-visp-rand-day-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-paris-lyon-geneve-visp-rand-day-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KDE Multimedia Sprint Paris, day -1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In my way to Randa where the Multimedia Sprint will take place I'm doing a stop in my brothers house, among the obvious reasons (see my brother) I'm here because the overall price of the travel was 20€ cheaper and because I love &amp;quot;Nutella crepes&amp;quot; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the plane I have been working on QuickSand (the KRunner alternative interface), basically what I'm doing is to remove the hardcoded colors so that it can be used on any kind of colors scheme (I'm using a dark one right now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finish the fine tuning I'll public a small video about QuickSand, I'm not going to add any new features but I think it is an interesting unknown part of the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/DSC04757.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;French dessert&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-paris-day-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kde-multimedia-sprint-paris-day-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Audio and input support in KBluetooth :)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, the most wanted feature has landed in KBluetooth, support for Audio!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The support is divided in 4 blocks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pair the device&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The support for pair the devices should be working, not only for HEADSETS but for everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect to the service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;KBluetooth will detect if the paired device has audio service, and connect to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support for PulseAudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PulseAudio rocks, and since it rocks it will detect and configure the new device automagically :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support for Alsa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alsa is not automagical like PulseAudio, so we've to write a few things in a file to get it working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is done by KBluetooth but Alsa support, so I'll explain how to get it working manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-Pair it using kbluetooth-wizard (be sure that you're using kbluetooth-wizard an not kbluetooth-&lt;strong&gt;input&lt;/strong&gt;wizard)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-Launch kbluetooth-devicemanager, click in your headset and write somewhere the Address (XX:XX:XX:XX:XX:XX)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3-Open with your favorite editor the file ~/.asoundrc (located in your home) and add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;pcm.bluetooth {&lt;br /&gt;type bluetooth&lt;br /&gt;device 00:11:22:33:44:55&lt;br /&gt;profile &amp;quot;auto&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-If you want use it with Phonon, try the following configuration (is not working totally but something is something :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;pcm.softvol {&lt;br /&gt;type softvol&lt;br /&gt;slave {&lt;br /&gt;pcm &amp;quot;bluetooth&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;control {&lt;br /&gt;name &amp;quot;SoftMaster&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;card 0&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;hint {&lt;br /&gt;show on&lt;br /&gt;description &amp;quot;BlueTooth Headset&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;pcm.bluetooth {&lt;br /&gt;type bluetooth&lt;br /&gt;device 00:11:22:33:44:55&lt;br /&gt;profile &amp;quot;auto&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, a Bluetooth device should appear in KDE-Multimedia configuration, but as I said is not full working (If I recall correctly the output was working perfectly but not the input).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the corresponding video:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/audioandinput.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt; &lt;a href='http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/audioandinput.ogv'&gt;Download video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/audio-and-input-support-in-kbluetooth/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/audio-and-input-support-in-kbluetooth/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KBluetooth freezeless Wizard:)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm not a fussy user, I mean I don't really care so much about interfaces or usability (as an user of course, as a developer I try to do my best), wherever there is a terminal I feel like home in there. However, in the other hand, when I'm developing I need to feel comfortable with the environment, including the application I'm developing. It's for this reason that I've prioritized the GUI polishing of the wizard (the old one pissed me off every time I had to test something).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And well, this is the result, a freezeeless interface for KBluetooth-wizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/wizard-freezeless.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: As a sneak-peak, notice that the wizard is not longer called &quot;inputwizard :)&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saluts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-freezeless-wizard/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-freezeless-wizard/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Feel a &quot;natural flow&quot; in your desktop (Panel at the top)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As my friends know, I'm addicted to read KDE/Free Software/Open Source/etc.. blogs when taking my morning coffee, and what I'm going to explain is a good example of why I love it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before continuing reading, be aware that I'm not an usability guy, I lack any kind of design or usability sense/knowledgement, In fact, I have been I'm using KDE for years and I never succeed to configure my desktop in a beautiful way (only by copying the others configs), so please keep that in your mind when you read this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, Celeste wrote an excellent paper about &amp;quot;Tabs in the Taskbar&amp;quot;. After reading it I decided to move my panel to the top of my main screen. The result has exceeded my expectations. What I got is more than a better relationship between the panel and the applications, what I got is something I've named a &amp;quot;Natural flow&amp;quot;, let me try to explain what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I noticed after placing the panel at the top of the screen was that I forced less my eyes. Because of my work, I need to be aware of the notifications (kmail), but at the same time I'm usually writing code so I'm never watching the bottom of the screen, in fact if there is a part of the screen that I totally ignore it is the bottom, so move my eyes to that part of the screen every time I got a notification was painful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing I realize a few hours after, was a harder connection between applications and the taskbar. For example I have always ignored the &amp;quot;request attention&amp;quot; thing of the taskbar items, now I guess that because my eyes are &amp;quot;half watching&amp;quot; the taskbar all the time I'm able to notice the blinking quickly. Also the taskbar is acting now as a &amp;quot;Tab bar&amp;quot;, it also works for applications that are in a different screen or not are maximized thanks of KWIN maximize/minimize effects,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final thing, is something that may sound stupid to you (It did to me!), it is that menus/notifications/plasmoids etc show up from the top to the bottom. In earth thanks of gravity objects fall down, and I think that it's because of this that I feel this behavior more natural than the other one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! keep the panel at the top a day and decide where you like it more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ps: Please, do not flame in the comments, the objective of this entry is to share my experience with other people not to start an usability flame or something like that. Usability is a complex subject, and I ignore all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/feel-a-natural-flow-in-your-desktop-panel-at-the-top/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/feel-a-natural-flow-in-your-desktop-panel-at-the-top/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What a small thing. what a great improvement (configure your font settings)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there! no, this post is not about Kbluetooth nor KTuberling or any development/technical stuff, is more a user-like post, so common! keep reading this time :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was in the office with ereslibre showing something to him (I don't remember what), when he noticed something in my desktop that he didn't liked, my fonts. I laughed quite a lot because I thought that it was a &amp;quot;Yet Another Small Detail That Ereslibre Cares Of&amp;quot;. I let him modify my settings so I could say later to him: you see? this thing has not improved my user experience in any way. But as you probably guessed by now, I was terribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, now I'm pushing everybody I know which uses KDE to setup the same configuration I have. I don't really know what the hell the parameters I modify means, but what I know is that now I'm happier with my desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The famous settings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Font: Dejavu Sans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use anti-aliasing: Enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Click on configure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use sub-pixel rendering: RGB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hinting style: Slight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In screenshots (so you can extrapolate it to your language):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the font and enable the anti-aliasing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fonts_1.png&quot; title=&quot;Fonts settings 1&quot; alt=&quot;Fonts settings 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click on configure and set the subpixel rendering:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fonts_2.png&quot; title=&quot;Fonts settings 2&quot; alt=&quot;Fonts settings 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the hinting styke:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fonts_3.png&quot; title=&quot;Fonts settings 3&quot; alt=&quot;Fonts settings 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last KDE user I &amp;quot;moved&amp;quot; to these settings has needed 1 day to notice the changes, so just do it and wait :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powered by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/'&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/what-a-small-thing-what-a-great-improvement-configure-your-font-settings/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/what-a-small-thing-what-a-great-improvement-configure-your-font-settings/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fulfilling promises, Apple Wireless Keyboard working with KBluetooth</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi fellow users and developers, sooner than I thought, I have more things to share with you about KBluetooth, so let's go :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happens that month's ago &lt;a title=&quot;Apol blog&quot; href=&quot;http://www.proli.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apol &lt;/a&gt; lent me his Apple Wireless Keyboard so I can give support to it in KBluetooth. After small research I concluded that the keyboard wasn't standard, so I just pull it over. Then, a few days ago, Ereslibre was playing with a Gnome and I decided to try to pair the Apple keyboard using the Gnome Bluetooth System, and guess what... it worked !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today, I decided do not go to sleep until I got it working, and here I am, 03:12 and writting this entry with that keyboard :)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; autobuffer=&quot;false&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/applebluetooth.ogv&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This feature, should fix the keyboard pairing completely, not matter if your keyboard is the Apple one or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature will be available in the next version (0.5) together with a new Wizard and maybe a new (or at least improved) device manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can test your &quot;non-working&quot; keyboard with the trunk version and give me some feedback, I'll be very appreciated :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya and Happy Hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/fulfilling-promises-apple-wireless-keyboard-working-with-kbluetooth/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/fulfilling-promises-apple-wireless-keyboard-working-with-kbluetooth/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>As promised, KBluetooth 0.4.2</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes the (hopefully) last version of KBluetooth stable branch. The change list is not very huge (only fixes) but if there is something I'm glad to have fixed is the speed calculation of the file transfers, it was so annoying for me to see the text blinking ;(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changelog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix speed calculation when receiving and sending filesI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pairing request are accepted also when clicking on Trust button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important dialogs are modal, so they're not hidden by other applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a crash that happens when the sender device disconnects before the file transfer is accepted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small note, the Modals will be removed in the next version, this is a bug fix release so the less code I change, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I'll start to work on 0.5 more intensively, starting by adding a2dp support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;KBluetooth file transfer&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/gui_platform3.png&quot; alt=&quot;KBluetooth file transfer&quot; width=&quot;473&quot; height=&quot;243&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/as-promised-kbluetooth-0-4-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/as-promised-kbluetooth-0-4-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Yet Another Delayed FOSDEM Entry</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With a week of delay (almost) is time to write my sum up of FOSDEM, which by the way was my first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday 05/02/2010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wake up at 3:00 AM to take a cab to go to Barajas airport, I have to say that Gate 2 is uglier than the Gate 2 of El prat airport (and smaller), but one point in favor is that it was full of power sources :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in Brussels, Kiko, Victor and Oscar were waiting for me, I got some stress because of the airport distribution, is like labyrinth! Then usual route in that kind of travels, Breakfast-&amp;gt;Hotel-&amp;gt;Launch-&amp;gt;FOSDEM beer event. A well, between Launch and FOSDEM we went to Brussels MIDI to met Aleix pol (apol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the FOSDEM beer event, I'm not going to say anything new, lot of good beer, a lot of hackers around and good chat. Maybe I was expecting more free beer :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 06/02/2010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mueheh perhaps because I was excited for my first FOSDEM, everything look wonderful to me, and one small detail I'm still enjoining was the way the donations were done: they gave us a receipt so it looked more like more official/serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aleix pol has already blogged about kamoso appearing in the opensuse stand, it was a good surprise! (I can not image what the people of opensuse were thinking when apol and I started to laughing and taking pictures xD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I found weird (and disappointed me) was that the Mandriva ppl didn't have any computer with KDE :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the talks, we were in KDE room almost all the day, so there's not much to say about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 07/02/2010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day had a proper noun, Andrew_S._Tanenbaum, this is a short summary but it made my day. Another interesting thing was my chat with Will Stephenson about Bluetooth+KDE, I'm sure that what we discussed will have good effects in the KDE Bluetooth world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small note for future FOSDEM newbies: wearing a t-shirt of a project in which you are not involved IS NOT A GOOD IDEA! the people will think that you're a developer of it and will start to ask you a lot of questions xD!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental note: Next year bring KDE t-shirts.&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC04604.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large  wp-image-130&quot; title=&quot;Vintage Brussels&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC04604-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;869&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;Blogilo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/yet-another-delayed-fosdem-entry/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/yet-another-delayed-fosdem-entry/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>KBluetooth 0.4.1</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 0.4 release I asked to the distributions to update they packages, some of them did and some of then not, but the best of all is that I got a lot of feedback from the packagers, and here comes the payment for that feedback :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the last release I added a crash when receiving files, I gare say it was not my fault, the KBluetooth code is a mess and I can't fix it without rewrite it from scratch (thing that I'll explain hopefully in 2 days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small roadmap for 0.4 version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix file transfer jobs (speed calculation and notifications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check (and re-check again) input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try to get the above points covered in a couple of days too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=-=-=-=-=&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Powered by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogilo.gnufolks.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blogilo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-0-4-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-0-4-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I'm going to FOSDEM too!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Seems that this year a lot of KDE hackers will go to FOSDEM and I won't be an exception :)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not defined my roadmap (yet), but at least I'll have a couple of meeting regarding the future of KBluetooth, and sooner than you think I'll come back with great news about Bluetooth+KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're in the FOSDEM and you have doubts or ideas about Bluetooth+KDE ping to me I'll be around *KDE* stuff in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cya!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/im-going-to-fosdem-too/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/im-going-to-fosdem-too/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kbluetooth 0.4 is here!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Months ago, I started to take care of a forgotten piece of KDE, kde-bluetooth. After a lot of work and an almost clean the bugtrack of bugs, I'm proud to announce KBluetooth 0.4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official name is now &amp;quot;KBluetooth&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of crashes have been fixed, KBluetooth should not crash now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File transfer (send/receive) reported to work for everybody with any kind of device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the input pairing (Almost all devices working).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge improvements in the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The speed in notifications is not accurate nor working right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes for packagers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the first RC, I only had fixed BUGS, and almost every commit since then contains an atomic fix, so please upgrade to the 0.4 final or apply the patches yourself, but do not get stuck in the previous RC's, doing that you'll waste the time of your bugtracker people, as well of kde bugtracker crew and mine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tag has been created in tags/kbluetooth/0.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note for users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask to your distribution for the final 0.4 version of KBluetooth, the only and original one :)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next days, I'll write a series of entries about KBluetooth, the list is not final tough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of KBluetooth 0.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with KBluetooth (Developers and users)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short term future, KBluetooth 0.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE+Bluetooth future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kde-apps.org/content/show.php/kbluetooth?content=112110&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://kde-apps.org/content/show.php/kbluetooth?content=112110&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-0-4-is-here/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/kbluetooth-0-4-is-here/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Resuming my adventure in KDE</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is time to resume my adventure in the lands of KDE, I had to stop it because of work, I'm creating a new business together with ereslibre and edulix and we are kind of busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the topic, in this second part of the adventure I'm not going to change my focus, so I'll continue hacking on kbluetooth, kamoso and ktuberling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes a small todo list I'll try to accomplish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish 0.4 release of KBluetooth (2 crashes to be fixed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release KBluetooth 0.5 (I'll talk about it in a other blog post).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post at least once a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to develop the new Bluetooth solution for KDE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish KTuberling easy switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kamoso++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KTuberling++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I'd like to hack on is the xrandr support, but I don't want to open more fronts not until at least I have kio_bluetooth working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And well, this is all! I hope to blog in a few days announcing KBluetooth 0.4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post written using Blogilo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/resuming-my-adventure-in-kde/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/resuming-my-adventure-in-kde/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I don't like why, but I'm the new maintainer of KTuberling</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As everybody should know by now, tsdgeos is moving to another city (Dublin) and of course is getting a new job. Is because of this job that Albert is not able to continue with his collaboration with anything that have to be with games. Life sometimes has this unintended consequences :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So well, as you know, I created a patch some month/weeks ago which adds a small feature to KTuberling (will be available in kde 4.5). Since I like the code, and I'm a &quot;friend? :p&quot; of tsdgeos I proposed myself to Albert to continue with KTuberling at least until he can go back to his *games* duties :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is my roadmap for KTuberling in KDE SC (KSC?, I don't like the new branding sorry ._.) 4.5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Support to switch between playgrounds using easier way&lt;br /&gt;
2. Possibility to export the playground in some simple web 2.0 service&lt;br /&gt;
3. Add Get Hot New Stuff  (in discussion)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any ideas please, drop a bug to bugs.kde.org so we can evaluate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/new-ktuberling-maintaine/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/new-ktuberling-maintaine/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>À bientôt, Paris</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;At home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my &quot;small&quot; holidays in Paris, I'm back home. Despite my intentions of finishing some ktuberling/kamoso/kbluetooth work on this holidays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as you may have noticed I didn't, sorry for that :( I only had time to keep myself up to date with kde planet/mailist/commits, leaving only the last 3 days of kde activities as homework to when I'll come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, I've read everything I had to, as well as answering dozens of emails and I'm ready to hack on KDE again and to finish my kde homework's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I'm going to do is to prepare the release of kbluetooth 0.4, as well as to write the property announcement of the project, which will be splited in 3/4 post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then some more work on Kamoso will follow (add webcam basic controls), and finally I have to finish the ktuberling patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all at the moment!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; caption=&quot;Picture from Effiel top // Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share Alike&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/seeyouparis_full.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;   &quot; title=&quot;Good bye paris picture&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/seeyouparis.png&quot; alt=&quot;Picture from torre effiel top&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;385&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon Paris :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/a-bientot-paris/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/a-bientot-paris/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>In Paris until 02/11/2009</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As maybe you have noticed I'm kinda offline these days, this is because I'm in Paris in some sort of holidays. While I'm here my internet/code hours will be reduced to the mornings, from 10:00 to 14:00 (local hour), I'm using the rest of the day for walking trough those beautiful streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is it at the moment,  tomorrow I'll announce something in this blog, something that lot of people has been waiting for :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;alignnone&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; caption=&quot;Effiel picture against the sun // Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share Alike&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/DSC01983.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;   &quot; title=&quot;Effiel picture&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.afiestas.org/files/parisBlog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Effiel picture against the sun&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;385&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the picture to download it in his original size, if somebody wants the raw just ask for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://afiestas.org/in-paris-until-02112009/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://afiestas.org/in-paris-until-02112009/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
